Why don't you go ahead?  Sit down and see if you can get comfy.
好 你直接开始吧？ ‎好 坐下 能否舒适地坐着
You good?   All right.   Yeah.
还好吗？  好了  ‎是
Take one, marker.
‎第一镜 打板
Wanna start by introducing yourself?
要我先从自我介绍开始吗？
Hello, world. Bailey. Take three.
‎世界你好 贝利 第三镜
You good?    This is the worst part, man.
可以了吗？ ‎  这是我最讨厌的部分 兄弟
I don't like this.
‎我不喜欢这样
I worked at Facebook in 2011 and 2012.
‎我2011年到2012年间在脸书工作
I was one of the really early employees at Instagram.
‎我是Instagram非常早期的员工
I worked at, uh, Google, uh, YouTube.
‎我曾任职于谷歌、YouTube
Apple, Google, Twitter, Palm.
‎苹果、谷歌、推特、Palm
I helped start Mozilla Labs and switched over to the Firefox side.
‎我帮助创始了Mozilla Labs ‎后来更多工作于火狐这边
Are we rolling?  Everybody?
‎在拍吗？大家…
Great.
‎很好
I worked at Twitter.
‎我曾在推特工作
My last job there
我在推特的 ‎
was the senior vice president of engineering.
最后一份岗位 是高级副总工程师
I was the president of Pinterest.
‎我曾是Pinterest的总经理
Before that, um, I was the... the director of monetization
‎在那之前 我在脸书做了五年的
at Facebook for five years.
‎盈利总监
While at Twitter, I spent a number of years running their developer platform,
‎在推特期间 我用了几年时间 ‎运营他们的开发者平台
and then I became head of consumer product.
‎然后我做了消费者产品部长
I was the  coinventor of Google Drive, Gmail Chat,
‎我曾合作发明 ‎谷歌硬盘、谷歌邮箱聊天
Facebook Pages, and the Facebook like button.
‎脸书网页和脸书“赞”按钮
Yeah. This is... This is why I spent, like, eight months
‎对 所以我才花了八个月的时间
talking back and forth with lawyers.
‎和律师反复周旋
This freaks me out.
‎真的让我很崩溃
When I was there,
‎我在那里任职的时候
I always felt like, fundamentally, it was a force for good.
一直觉得 ‎总体上 这是积极的力量
I don't know if I feel that way anymore.
‎我现在不确定 自己是否还这样想了
I left Google in June 2017, uh, due to ethical concerns.
‎出于对道德伦理的担心 ‎我于2017年6月离开谷歌
And... And not just at Google but within the industry at large.
‎不仅是担心谷歌的道德伦理 ‎而是对整个产业
I'm very concerned.
‎我很担心
‎非常担心
It's easy today to lose sight of the fact
‎如今 人们很容易忽略一个事实
that these tools actually have created some wonderful things in the world.
‎这些工具 ‎其实为世界创造了一些美好的东西
They've reunited lost family members. They've found organ donors.
‎它们让失去联系的家人重聚 ‎找器官捐赠者
I mean, there were meaningful, systemic changes happening
‎它们为整个世界带来了
around the world because of these platforms
‎有意义的、系统的变革
that were positive!
‎这是这些平台积极的一面
I think we were naive about the flip side of that coin.
‎我认为我们对它的消极一面 ‎过度看轻了
Yeah, these things, you release them, and they take on a life of their own.
‎对 这些东西 只要你发布 ‎它们自己就会存活
And how they're used is pretty different than how you expected.
‎它们被使用的方式 ‎与你当初的预期大相径庭
Nobody, I deeply believe, ever intended any of these consequences.
‎我深信 这些负面的后果 ‎不是任何人刻意为之
There's no one bad guy. No. Absolutely not.
‎没有任何一个坏人 没有 绝对没有
So, then, what's the... what's the problem?
‎那么问题在哪里？
Is there a problem, and what is the problem?
‎是否有问题？问题在哪里？
Yeah, it is hard to give a single, succinct...
‎是 很难给出一个单一的、简明的…
I'm trying to touch on many different problems.
‎我在试着谈论很多不同的问题
What is the problem?
‎问题在哪里？
‎NETFLIX 原创纪录片
Despite facing mounting criticism,
‎虽然面对越来越多的质疑
the so  called Big Tech names are getting bigger.
‎这些所谓的大型技术公司却越发壮大
The entire tech industry is under a new level of scrutiny.
‎整个技术产业 ‎正在面临全新维度的审查
And a new study sheds light on the link
‎一项新的研究初步揭示了心理健康
between mental health and social media use.
‎与社交媒体使用之间的联系
Here to talk about the latest research...
‎来谈谈最新的研究…
...is going on that gets no coverage at all.
‎…的情况 根本没有保险
Tens of millions of Americans are hopelessly addicted
‎数千万美国人无望地
to their electronic devices.
‎玩电子设备成瘾
It's exacerbated by the fact
‎因为技术 现在你真的能把自己
that you can literally isolate yourself now
‎隔离在一个泡泡内 周围都是
‎（你的朋友在照片中圈出了你）
in a bubble, thanks to our technology.
‎与你观点相似的人 ‎瘾性就更加恶化了
Fake news is becoming more advanced
‎虚假新闻变得更发达了
and threatening societies around the world.
‎威胁着全世界的社会
We weren't expecting any of this when we created Twitter over 12 years ago.
‎我们12年多以前创造推特的时候 ‎根本没有想到这些
White House officials say they have no reason to believe
‎官方说 他们没有理由相信
the Russian cyberattacks will stop.
‎俄罗斯网络攻击会停止
YouTube is being forced to concentrate on cleansing the site.
‎YouTube被迫专注于清理网站
TikTok, if you talk to any tween out there...
‎如果你和十几岁的孩子去聊
...there's no chance they'll delete this thing...
‎他们是绝对不可能删除抖音的…
Hey, Isla, can you get the table ready, please?
‎喂 艾拉 可以帮忙摆桌子吗？
There's a question about whether social media
‎有一个严肃的问题
is making your child depressed.
‎社交媒体是否让您的孩子抑郁
Isla, can you set the table, please?
‎艾拉 可以帮忙摆桌子吗？
These cosmetic procedures are becoming so popular with teens,
‎整容在青少年中已经十分受欢迎
plastic surgeons have coined a new syndrome for it,
‎整容医生甚至造出了一种新病征
"Snapchat dysmorphia," with young patients wanting surgery
‎“图片分享畸形征” ‎指的是年轻的患者想做整容手术
so they can look more like they do in filtered selfies.
‎让自己看上去 ‎更接近加了滤镜的自拍中的样子
Still don't see why you let her have that thing.
‎我还是不明白 ‎你为什么让她用那东西
What was I supposed to do?
‎我能怎么办？
I mean, every other kid in her class had one.
‎我是说 她们班上的其他孩子全都有
She's only 11.
‎她才11岁
Cass, no one's forcing you to get one.
‎卡桑 没人强迫你用
You can stay disconnected as long as you want.
‎你想和别人切断联系多久 都随你
Hey, I'm connected without a cell phone, okay?  I'm on the Internet right now.
‎喂 我没有手机也不会和别人 ‎切断联系 好吗？我现在就在网上
Also, that isn't even actual connection. It's just a load of sh
‎而且 这根本不是实际的联系 ‎全都是没用的…
Surveillance capitalism has come to shape
‎监视资本主义 ‎已经形成了我们的政治和文化
our politics and culture in ways many people don't perceive.
‎而很多人根本没有察觉
ISIS inspired followers online,
‎伊斯兰国煽动网上的关注者
and now white supremacists are doing the same.
‎现在 白人至上主义也在这样做
Recently in India,
‎最近在印度
Internet lynch mobs have killed a dozen people, including these five...
‎网络暴民害死了十几个人 ‎包括这五个…
It's not just fake news; it's fake news with consequences.
‎虚假新闻不只是虚假新闻 ‎是有后果的
How do you handle an epidemic in the age of fake news?
‎在虚假新闻的时代 ‎你要怎么解决传染病？
Can you get the coronavirus by eating Chinese food?
‎吃中餐会感染新冠病毒吗？
We have gone from the information age into the disinformation age.
‎我们已经从信息时代 ‎过渡到了虚假信息时代
Our democracy is under assault.
‎我们的民主受到了攻击
What I said was, "I think the tools
‎我说的是：“我认为如今 ‎
that have been created today are starting
创造出的工具正在开始
to erode the social fabric of how society works."
‎侵蚀社会正常运转的社交纽带”
Aza does welcoming remarks. We play the video.
‎阿莎愿意接受评论 我们播放视频
And then, "Ladies and gentlemen, Tristan Harris."
‎然后说 “女士们先生们 ‎我是特里斯坦·哈里斯”
Right.      Great.
‎  好 ‎  很好
So, I come up, and...
‎就是说 我上来 然后…
‎（人道 技术的新议程）
basically say, "Thank you all for coming." Um...
‎你就说“欢迎各位的到来”
So, today, I wanna talk about a new agenda for technology.
‎今天 我想聊聊技术的一个新议程
And why we wanna do that is because if you ask people,
‎以及我们为什么要这样做 ‎因为如果你问人们
"What's wrong in the tech industry right now? "
‎“如今的技术产业怎么了？”
there's a cacophony of grievances and scandals,
‎有一种不满和丑闻的杂音
and "They stole our data." And there's tech addiction.
‎“他们盗用了我们的数据” ‎还有技术成瘾问题
And there's fake news. And there's polarization
‎有虚假新闻问题 有两极分化问题
and some elections that are getting hacked.
‎有些竞选过程被黑客操控的问题
But is there something that is beneath all these problems
‎但是这些问题的背后 ‎是否有一个原因
that's causing all these things to happen at once?
‎导致这些问题在同时发生？
Does this feel good?    Very good. Yeah.
‎  感觉还行吗？ ‎  非常好 好
I'm just trying to... Like, I want people to see...
‎我只是想… 我想让人们看到…
Like, there's a problem happening in the tech industry,
‎在技术产业 正面临着一个问题
and it doesn't have a name,
‎这个问题连名字都没有 ‎
and it has to do with one source, like, one...
这个问题有一个源头…
When you look around you, it feels like the world is going crazy.
‎环顾你身边 ‎感觉这个世界在逐渐疯狂
You have to ask yourself, like, "Is this normal?
‎你要问自己 这是正常的吗？
Or have we all fallen under some kind of spell? "
‎还是我们都中了什么魔咒？
‎（特里斯坦·哈里斯 ‎谷歌前设计道德伦理学家）
‎（人道技术中心 合作创始人）
I wish more people could understand how this works
‎我希望更多的人能够理解它的原理
because it shouldn't be something that only the tech industry knows.
‎因为它不应该 ‎只被技术产业的业内知道
It should be something that everybody knows.
‎应该让所有人都知道
Bye.
拜
Hello!      Hi.
‎  你好！ ‎  嗨！
Tristan. Nice to meet you.   It's Tris  tan, right?
‎  特里斯坦 幸会 ‎  特里斯坦？
Yes.   Awesome. Cool.
‎  对 ‎  太好了 好
Tristan Harris is a former design ethicist for Google
‎特里斯坦·哈里斯 ‎是谷歌前设计道德伦理学家
and has been called the closest thing Silicon Valley has to a conscience.
‎被称为硅谷最接近良知的人物
He's asking tech
‎他呼吁技术产业
to bring what he calls "ethical design" to its products.
‎在产品中引进 ‎被他称为“道德伦理设计”的要素
It's rare for a tech insider to be so blunt,
‎搞技术的业内人士 ‎极少如此直言不讳
but Tristan Harris believes someone needs to be.
‎特里斯坦·哈里斯相信 ‎总有人要这样
When I was at Google,
‎我在谷歌工作的时候
I was on the Gmail team, and I just started getting burnt out
‎我在谷歌邮箱团队 ‎我就开始觉得很疲惫
'cause we'd had so many conversations about...
‎因为我们讨论了很多…
you know, what the inbox should look like and what color it should be, and...
‎收件箱应该长什么样 ‎应该是什么颜色
And I, you know, felt personally addicted to e  mail,
‎我自己感觉对邮件成瘾
and I found it fascinating
‎我觉得有趣的是
there was no one at Gmail working on making it less addictive.
‎在谷歌邮箱工作的人 ‎没有一个想把它做得不那么致瘾
And I was like, "Is anybody else thinking about this?
‎我想：“别人想过这个问题吗？
I haven't heard anybody talk about this."
‎我 没听谁谈论过这个问题”
And I was feeling this frustration...
‎我对技术产业
...with the tech industry, overall,
整体感到沮丧
that we'd kind of, like, lost our way.
‎感觉我们有点迷路了
You know, I really struggled to try and figure out
‎我真的很努力地去尝试 想办法
how, from the inside, we could change it.
‎怎样能从行业内部改变这个问题
And that was when I decided to make a presentation,
‎就在这个时候 我决定做一次展示
kind of a call to arms.
‎算是号召大家吧
Every day, I went home and I worked on it for a couple hours every single night.
‎每天我回到家 每一个晚上 ‎都要花几个小时去做这件事
It basically just said, you know,
‎我的呼吁是
never before in history have 50 designers
历史上从来没有过50个
20   to 35  year  old white guys in California
‎20到35岁之间的加州白人设计师
made decisions that would have an impact on two billion people.
‎做出一个能影响20亿人的决定
Two billion people will have thoughts that they didn't intend to have
‎20亿人将会拥有 ‎他们从来不曾预料的想法
because a designer at Google said, "This is how notifications work
‎只因为一个谷歌的设计师说 ‎“你每天早上醒来
on that screen that you wake up to in the morning."
‎屏幕上的通知就是这样工作的”
And we have a moral responsibility, as Google, for solving this problem.
‎我们作为谷歌 ‎有解决这个问题的道德责任
And I sent this presentation
‎我把这个展示
to about 15, 20 of my closest colleagues at Google,
‎发给了在谷歌 ‎与我关系最近的15到20个同事
and I was very nervous about it. I wasn't sure how it was gonna land.
‎我很紧张 我不知道他们会怎样想
When I went to work the next day,
‎我第二天去上班的时候
most of the laptops had the presentation open.
‎多数的电脑上都开着这个展示
Later that day, there was, like, 400 simultaneous viewers,
‎那天下午 有400个人同时观看
so it just kept growing and growing.
‎看到的人越来越多
I got e  mails from all around the company. I mean, people in every department saying,
‎我收到整个公司同事发来的各种邮件 ‎每一个部门的人都说
"I totally agree." "I see this affecting my kids."
‎“我太同意了 ‎我看到这个问题正在影响我的孩子
"I see this affecting the people around me."
‎我看到这个问题正在影响我身边的人
"We have to do something about this."
‎我们应该做点什么 来解决这个问题”
It felt like I was sort of launching a revolution or something like that.
‎我感觉自己 ‎好像开启了一场革命之类的
Later, I found out Larry Page had been notified about this presentation
‎后来 我才知道莱利·佩吉 ‎那一天在三个不同会议
in three separate meetings that day.
‎都被人告知这个展示的存在
And so, it created this kind of cultural moment
‎于是这个展示 ‎创造了这个文化性的时刻
that Google needed to take seriously.
‎谷歌需要认真对待
And then... nothing.
‎然后…杳无音讯了
Everyone in 2006...
‎2006年 所有人…
including all of us at Facebook,
‎包括我们在脸书的所有人
just had total admiration for Google and what Google had built,
‎超级羡慕谷歌 ‎羡慕谷歌所创建的一切
which was this incredibly useful service
‎超级实用的服务
that did, far as we could tell, lots of goodness for the world,
‎据我们当时所知 ‎为世界带来了很多好处
and they built this parallel money machine.
‎他们建立了一个平行的造钱机器
We had such envy for that, and it seemed so elegant to us...
‎我们超级羡慕嫉妒谷歌 ‎在我们看来太优雅了…
and so perfect.
‎太完美了
Facebook had been around for about two years,
‎脸书当时才成立大概两年
um, and I was hired to come in and figure out
‎我被雇到脸书
what the business model was gonna be for the company.
‎ 去找出公司未来要走怎样的商业模式
I was the director of monetization. The point was, like,
‎我曾是盈利总监 大概意思就是
"You're the person who's gonna figure out how this thing monetizes."
‎“你是要去想出 ‎这个东西怎样盈利的人”
And there were a lot of people who did a lot of the work,
‎当时很多人做了很多工作
but I was clearly one of the people who was pointing towards...
‎但我明显是其中一个指向…
"Well, we have to make money, A...
‎首先 我们必须要赚钱
and I think this advertising model is probably the most elegant way.
‎我认为这个广告模式 ‎可能是最优雅的方式
Uh  oh. What's this video Mom just sent us?
‎妈妈刚给我们发的什么视频？
Oh, that's from a talk show, but that's pretty good.
‎一个脱口秀 不过挺不错的 ‎
Guy's kind of a genius.
那个人还算是个天才
He's talking all about deleting social media, which you gotta do.
‎他在谈论删除社交媒体 ‎你们真应该这样做
I might have to start blocking her e  mails.
‎我可能要开始屏蔽她的邮件了
I don't even know what she's talking about, man.
‎讲真 我都不知道她在说什么 ‎天啊
She's worse than I am.
她还不如我
No, she only uses it for recipes.   Right, and work.
‎  不 她只用来找菜谱 ‎  对 还有工作
And workout videos.      And to check up on us.
‎  还有健身视频 ‎  还看我们在做什么
And everyone else she's ever met in her entire life.
‎还看她这辈子遇到过的每一个人 ‎在做什么
If you are scrolling through your social media feed
‎如果你一边往下划着 ‎你的社交媒体推送
while you're watchin' us, you need to put the damn phone down and listen up
‎一边看着我们 ‎你需要把你该死的手机放下 听好
'cause our next guest has written an incredible book
‎因为我们的下一位嘉宾 ‎写了一本优秀的书
about how much it's wrecking our lives.
‎书的内容是社交媒体 ‎多大程度上破坏了我们的生活
Please welcome author
‎掌声有请
of Ten Arguments for Deleting Your Social Media Accounts Right Now...
《立刻删除 ‎你社交媒体的十个论点》作者
Uh  huh.   ...Jaron Lanier.
‎贾伦·拉尼尔
Companies like Google and Facebook are some of the wealthiest
‎谷歌、脸书这样的公司是有史以来
and most successful of all time.
‎最富有、最成功的几个公司
Uh, they have relatively few employees.
‎他们的员工数量相对较少
They just have this giant computer that rakes in money, right?  Uh...
‎他们只有一个大电脑 在那里摇钱
Now, what are they being paid for?
‎问题是 别人为什么给他们钱呢？ ‎
That's a really important question.
这是一个非常重要的问题
So, I've been an investor in technology for 35 years.
‎我做了35年的技术产业投资者
The first 50 years of Silicon Valley, the industry made products
‎硅谷的前50年 行业制造产品…
hardware, software
‎硬件、软件
sold 'em to customers. Nice, simple business.
卖给顾客 ‎简单良好的商业模式
For the last ten years, the biggest companies in Silicon Valley
‎过去十年 硅谷最大的公司
have been in the business of selling their users.
‎一直涉足贩卖他们用户的勾当
It's a little even trite to say now,
‎现在这样说 有点陈词滥调
but... because we don't pay for the products that we use,
‎但因为我们不为使用这些产品付钱
advertisers pay for the products that we use.
‎广告商为我们使用的产品付钱
Advertisers are the customers.
‎广告商是顾客
We're the thing being sold.
‎我们是被销售的商品
The classic saying is:
‎经典的说法是
"If you're not paying for the product, then you are the product."
‎“如果你没有花钱买产品 ‎那你就是被卖的产品”
A lot of people think, you know, "Oh, well, Google's just a search box,
‎很多人想：“谷歌只是一个搜索框
and Facebook's just a place to see what my friends are doing
‎脸书只是一个看我朋友们在做什么
and see their photos."
‎看他们照片的地方”
But what they don't realize is they're competing for your attention.
‎但他们没有意识到的是 ‎他们在竞争你的关注
So, you know, Facebook, Snapchat, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube,
‎脸书、阅后即焚图片分享、推特 ‎Instagram、YouTube
companies like this, their business model is to keep people engaged on the screen.
‎这种公司 他们的商业模式 ‎是让人们的注意力持续吸引在屏幕上
Let's figure out how to get as much of this person's attention
‎我们来想办法 怎样尽最大可能
as we possibly can.
‎获得这个人的注意力
How much time can we get you to spend?
‎我们能让你在上面花多少时间？
How much of your life can we get you to give to us?
‎我们能让你给我们分出 ‎你人生的多少时间？
When you think about how some of these companies work,
‎当你去想 这些公司是怎样运作的
it starts to make sense.
‎就能开始想通了
There are all these services on the Internet that we think of as free,
‎网络上有过各种服务 ‎我们都认为是免费的
but they're not free. They're paid for by advertisers.
‎但它们并不是免费的 ‎是广告商在付钱
Why do advertisers pay those companies?
‎广告商为什么给这些公司付钱？
They pay in exchange for showing their ads to us.
‎它们付钱 交换给你展示广告
We're the product. Our attention is the product being sold to advertisers.
‎我们是产品 我们的关注 ‎就是卖给广告商的产品
That's a little too simplistic.
‎这样说 过于简单化了
It's the gradual, slight, imperceptible change
‎产品其实是我们行为和认知的
in your own behavior and perception that is the product.
‎逐渐的、一点一点的 ‎我们未察觉到的变化
‎（行为和认知的 变化）
And that is the product. It's the only possible product.
‎这才是产品 是唯一可能的产品
There's nothing else on the table that could possibly be called the product.
‎这其中 没有任何东西 ‎能再被称为产品了
That's the only thing there is for them to make money from.
‎这是他们能拿来赚钱的唯一东西
Changing what you do,
‎改变你做的事
how you think, who you are.
‎你的思维模式 改变你这个人
It's a gradual change. It's slight.
‎这是一种逐渐的变化 非常轻微
If you can go to somebody and you say, "Give me $10 million,
‎如果你去找一个人 ‎你说：“给我一千万美元
and I will change the world one percent in the direction you want it to change..."
‎我会让世界往你希望的方向改变1%…”
It's the world! That can be incredible, and that's worth a lot of money.
‎是整个世界！这就很神奇 值很多钱
Okay.
‎好
This is what every business has always  dreamt of:
‎这是每种商业都一直梦想的
to have a guarantee that if it places an ad, it will be successful.
‎就是投放一个广告 ‎有一定能够成功的保证
That's their business.
‎这就是他们的生意 ‎
They sell certainty.
他们卖的是确定性
‎（确定性）
In order to be successful in that business,
‎为了在这个生意中成功
you have to have great predictions.
‎你必须要有优秀的预判能力
Great predictions begin with one imperative:
‎（优秀的预判能力）
‎优秀的预判能力始于一个必要条件
you need a lot of data.
‎你需要很多数据
‎（数据）
Many people call this surveillance capitalism,
‎很多人把它称作监视资本主义
capitalism profiting off of the infinite tracking
‎资本主义利用大型技术公司 ‎对每个人去的每一个地方
of everywhere everyone goes by large technology companies
‎进行无限追踪获利
whose business model is to make sure
‎大型技术公司的商业模式
that advertisers are as successful as possible.
‎是保证广告商能尽最大可能成功
This is a new kind of marketplace now.
‎这是现在的一种新市场
It's a marketplace that never existed before.
‎这种市场 以前从未出现过
And it's a marketplace that trades exclusively in human futures.
‎这个市场交易的 只有人类期货
Just like there are markets that trade in pork belly futures or oil futures.
‎就像交易五花肉期货 ‎和石油期货的市场
We now have markets that trade in human futures at scale,
‎我们现在有了 ‎交易大范围人类期货的市场
and those markets have produced the trillions of dollars
‎这些市场创造了万亿美元
that have made the Internet companies the richest companies
‎让网络公司成为了人类历史上
in the history of humanity.
‎最富有的公司
What I want people to know is that everything they're doing online
‎我想让人们知道的是 ‎他们在网上做的一切
is being watched, is being tracked, is being measured.
‎都被监控着 被追踪着 被评估着
Every single action you take is carefully monitored and recorded.
‎你所做出的每一个行为 ‎都被小心翼翼地监控着、记录着
Exactly what image you stop and look at, for how long you look at it.
‎具体到你停在哪一张图片上看了 ‎你看了多久
Oh, yeah, seriously, for how long you look at it.
‎是的 真的 看了多久都记录了
‎（纳维亚 参与时间）
‎（瑞恩 参与时间）
‎（雷恩 参与时间）
They know when people are lonely.
‎人们孤独的时候 他们知道 ‎
They know when people are depressed.
人们抑郁的时候 他们知道
They know when people are looking at photos of your ex  romantic partners.
‎人们看前任爱侣的时候 他们知道
They know what you're doing late at night. They know the entire thing.
‎你深夜在做什么 他们知道 ‎他们全都知道
Whether you're an introvert or an extrovert,
‎你是内向还是外向
or what kind of neuroses you have, what your personality type is like.
‎你的神经哪种类型 ‎你的性格是哪种类型
They have more information about us
‎他们所掌握的我们的信息
than has ever been imagined in human history.
‎超越人类历史上所有的想象
It is unprecedented.
‎这是史无前例的
And so, all of this data that we're... that we're just pouring out all the time
‎所有这些我们不经意间 ‎不断流露出的数据
is being fed into these systems that have almost no human supervision
‎都被输入到这些系统中 ‎几乎不用人类看管
and that are making better and better and better and better predictions
‎会做出越来越好的预判
about what we're gonna do and... and who we are.
‎预判出我们要做什么 ‎我们是怎样的人
‎（为您推荐）
People have the misconception it's our data being sold.
‎很多人有一种误解 认为被卖掉的 ‎是我们的数据
It's not in Facebook's business interest to give up the data.
‎脸书的商业兴趣 ‎肯定不是放掉这些数据
What do they do with that data?
‎他们用这些数据做什么呢？
They build models that predict our actions,
‎他们做出预判我们行为的模型
and whoever has the best model wins.
‎拥有最优秀模型的公司就赢了
His scrolling speed is slowing.
‎他向下滑网页的速度慢
Nearing the end of his average session length.
‎接近他平均阅读一屏时间长度的末尾
Decreasing ad load.
‎减少广告加载
Pull back on friends and family.
‎把朋友和家人弄回来
On the other side of the screen,
‎在屏幕的另一端
it's almost as if they had this avatar voodoo doll  like model of us.
‎他们就好像拥有一个 ‎我们的巫毒娃娃化身一样
All of the things we've ever done,
‎我们做过的所有事情
all the clicks we've ever made,
‎点击过的每一个地方
all the videos we've watched, all the likes,
‎我们看过的所有视频 ‎点赞过的所有内容
that all gets brought back into building a more and more accurate model.
‎这些数据都会被返回去 ‎用来建造一个越来越精准的模型
The model, once you have it,
‎一旦有了这个模型
you can predict the kinds of things that person does.
‎就能预判这个人做怎样的事
Right, let me just test.
‎好 让我测试一下
Where you'll go. I can predict  what kind of videos
‎你将要去哪里  ‎我能预判出 ‎
will keep you watching.
你会继续看什么样的视频
I can predict what kinds of emotions tend to trigger you.
‎我能预判 ‎什么样的情感更能让你产生共鸣
Yes, perfect.
‎好 完美
The most epic fails of the year.
‎年度最悲壮失败
‎（悲壮失败）
Perfect. That worked.   Following with another video.
‎  完美 有效果 ‎  接着另一个视频
Beautiful. Let's squeeze in a sneaker ad before it starts.
‎漂亮 在它开始之前 ‎我们插进去一个运动鞋广告
At a lot of technology companies,
‎很多这种技术公司
there's three main goals.
有三个主要目标
There's the engagement goal:
‎有一个参与度目标 ‎
to drive up your usage, to keep you scrolling.
增加你的使用 让你一直滑动屏幕
There's the growth goal:
‎有一个增长目标
to keep you coming back and inviting as many friends
‎让你不断回来 尽可能多地邀请朋友
and getting them to invite more friends.
‎让他们再邀请更多的朋友
And then there's the advertising goal:
‎还有一个广告目标 ‎
to make sure that, as all that's happening,
确保一切按照预期发展
we're making as much money as possible from advertising.
‎我们尽量多地从广告上挣钱
Each of these goals are powered by algorithms
‎每一个目标都由一个算法驱动
whose job is to figure out what to show you
‎算法的作用是找出 给你展示什么
to keep those numbers going up.
‎让数据上涨
We often talked about, at Facebook, this idea
‎我们在脸书 经常聊到这个想法
of being able to just dial that as needed.
‎能够按照我们的需要调控
And, you know, we talked about having Mark have those dials.
‎我们聊过 让马克来调控
"Hey, I want more users in Korea today."
‎“喂 我今天想让韩国的用户增加”
"Turn the dial."
‎开始调控
"Let's dial up the ads a little bit."
‎“我们调控提高一点广告”
"Dial up monetization, just slightly."
‎“调控提高一点盈利”
And so, that happ
‎所以说…
I mean, at all of these companies, there is that level of precision.
‎所有这些公司 ‎都能做到这种程度的精准
Dude, how       I don't know how I didn't get carded.
‎  兄弟 怎么… ‎  我不知道我怎么没有得到黄牌罚下
That ref just, like, sucked or something.   You got literally all the way...
‎  那个裁判真是逊 ‎  真的是一直…
That's Rebecca. Go talk to her.   I know who it is.
‎  那是瑞贝卡 去和她说话 ‎  我知道那是谁
Dude, yo, go talk to her.      I'm workin' on it.
‎  兄弟 去啊 去跟她说话 ‎  我正在努力
His calendar says he's on a break right now. We should be live.
‎他的日历上说 他正在休假 ‎我们应该实时操作
Want me to nudge him?
‎要我给他发一个窗口抖动吗？
Yeah, nudge away.
‎好 抖吧
"Your friend Tyler just joined. Say hi with a wave."
‎“您的好友泰勒刚刚加入了 ‎去挥手打个招呼吧”
Come on, Ben.
‎快啊 兄弟
Send a wave.
‎发一个挥手
You're not... Go talk to her, dude.
‎你都没有… 去和她说话 兄弟
‎您的好友泰勒刚刚加入了！ ‎挥手打个招呼吧
‎（联系人网络）
New link! All right, we're on.
‎新联系人！好 连上了
Follow that up with a post from User 079044238820, Rebecca.
‎接下来推送 ‎用户079044238820瑞贝卡的发帖
Good idea. GPS coordinates indicate that they're in close proximity.
‎好主意 卫星定位坐标显示 ‎他们距离很近
‎（瑞贝卡 找到了我的灵魂伴侣 ‎#闺蜜#呲溜呲溜#好朋友）
He's primed for an ad.
‎他容易受到广告影响
Auction time.
‎拍卖时间
‎（广告预览 深度衰落发蜡）
Sold! To Deep Fade hair wax.
‎卖了！给深度衰落发蜡
We had 468 interested bidders. We sold Ben at 3.262 cents for an impression.
‎我们有468个感兴趣的竞标人 ‎我们以3.262分卖给本 换来他的印象
We've created a world
‎我们创造了一个世界 ‎
in which online connection has become primary,
这个世界中 在线联系变成了主体
especially for younger generations.
‎尤其是对年轻一代
And yet, in that world, any time two people connect,
‎然而在这个世界 每次两个人联系
the only way it's financed is through a sneaky third person
‎唯一能提供经济支持的 ‎是通过一个鬼祟的第三方
who's paying to manipulate those two people.
‎有人给第三方钱 去操纵这两个人
So, we've created an entire global generation of people
‎所以 我们创造了全球的一整代人
who are raised within a context where the very meaning of communication,
‎他们成长的背景中 交流的意义
the very meaning of culture, is manipulation.
‎文化的意义 就是操纵
We've put deceit and sneakiness
‎我们所做的每一件事的中心
at the absolute center of everything we do.
‎都加入了欺骗和鬼祟
‎（“任何足够先进的技术 ‎都极其类似于魔术”）
‎（——亚瑟·C·克拉克）
Grab the...      Okay.
‎  拿起另一个… ‎  好
Where's it help to hold it?       Great.
‎  放在哪里才有用？ ‎  这样很好
Here?       Yeah.
‎  这里？ ‎  好
How does this come across on camera if I were to do, like, this move
‎这会怎样出现在摄影机中 ‎如果我要做…
We can          Like that?
‎  其实 我们可以… ‎  就这样？
What?    Yeah.
‎  什么？ ‎  对
Do that again.   Exactly. Yeah.
‎  再来一次？ ‎  没错 好
Yeah. No, it's probably not...
‎对 不是 可能不是…
Like... yeah.
‎这样… 对
I mean, this one is less...
‎这个就稍微没那么…
Larissa's, like, actually freaking out over here.
‎克里斯在那边已经烦死了
Is that good?
‎可以了吗？
‎（魔术！）
I was, like, five years old when I learned how to do magic.
‎我从五岁开始学习变魔术
And I could fool adults, fully  grown adults with, like,  PhDs.
‎我可以骗过成年人 ‎有博士学位的完全成熟的成年人
Magicians were almost like the first neuroscientists
‎魔术师几乎像是最早期的神经学家
and psychologists.
‎和心理学家
Like, they were the ones who first understood
‎他们是最先明白
how people's minds work.
‎人们思想工作原理的人
They just, in real time, are testing lots and lots of stuff on people.
‎他们在人们身上 ‎实时测试着很多很多的东西
A magician understands something,
‎魔术师懂一些事
some part of your mind that we're not aware of.
‎你思想中 ‎你自己都没意识到的某一部分
That's what makes the illusion work.
‎这是让幻觉起作用的关键
Doctors, lawyers, people who know how to build 747s or nuclear missiles,
‎医生、律师 ‎知道怎样构造747飞机或者核弹的人
they don't know more about how their own mind is vulnerable.
‎他们并不会比别人更了解 ‎自己的思想有多么脆弱
That's a separate discipline.
‎因为这是一个完全不用的学科领域
And it's a discipline that applies to all human beings.
‎这个学科领域 对所有人类都适用
‎（斯坦福大学）
From that perspective, you can have a very different understanding
‎从这个角度来说 ‎你就能对技术做了什么
of what technology is doing.
‎有一个不同的理解
When I was at the Stanford Persuasive Technology Lab,
‎我在斯坦福劝服技术实验室的时候 ‎
this is what we learned.
这就是我们所学到的
How could you use everything we know
‎怎样利用我们知道的一切心理学知识
about the psychology of what persuades people
‎什么东西能劝服人们
and build that into technology?
‎把这个运用到技术中？
Now, many of you in the audience are geniuses already.
‎在座观众中的很多人 已经是天才了
I think that's true, but my goal is to turn you into a behavior  change genius.
‎我认为这是事实 但我的目标是 ‎让你们变成行为改变的天才
There are many prominent Silicon Valley figures who went through that class
‎很多著名的硅谷人物 ‎都上过这个课
key growth figures at Facebook and Uber and... and other companies
‎脸书、优步和其他公司的 ‎业绩增长关键人物
and learned how to make technology more persuasive,
‎学习怎样让技术更能劝服人们
Tristan being one.
‎特里斯坦就是其中一个
Persuasive technology is just sort of design
‎劝服性技术 可以说是极端应用的
intentionally applied to the extreme,
‎刻意设计
where we really want to modify someone's behavior.
‎我们真的想去修改一个人的行为
We want them to take this action.
‎我们想让他们这样做
We want them to keep doing this with their finger.
‎我们想让他们继续用手指这样做
You pull down and you refresh, it's gonna be a new thing at the top.
‎你往下拉 刷新 最上面就是新的内容
Pull down and refresh again, it's new. Every single time.
‎再下拉 再刷新 又是新的 ‎每一次都是
Which, in psychology, we call a positive intermittent reinforcement.
‎在心理学上 我们称为“正积极强化”
You don't know when you're gonna get it or if you're gonna get something,
‎你不知道什么时候能刷到 ‎或者你是否能刷到什么
which operates just like the slot machines in Vegas.
‎它的原理就像是赌城的老虎机
It's not enough that you use the product consciously,
‎你有意识地使用产品 还远远不够
I wanna dig down deeper into the brain stem
‎我想深度侵入你的大脑根部
and implant, inside of you, an unconscious habit
‎在你脑中植入一个无意识的习惯
so that you are being programmed at a deeper level.
‎让你在更深的层次被编程
You don't even realize it.
‎你自己都没有意识到
A man, James Marshall...
‎一个叫做詹姆斯·马歇尔的人
Every time you see it there on the counter,
‎每一次你在看到老虎机在柜台上
and you just look at it, and you know if you reach over,
‎你看一眼 你知道如果你过去
it just might have something for you,
‎它可能有东西给你
so you play that slot machine to see what you got, right?
‎于是你就玩了一下老虎机 ‎看你能得到什么 对吧？
That's not by accident. That's a design technique.
‎这不是偶然 这是设计好的手段
He brings a golden nugget to an officer in the army in San Francisco.
‎他把一个金块 ‎给了旧金山军队的一个军官
Mind you, the... the population of San Francisco was only...
‎别忘了 旧金山的人口数量 ‎当时只有…
Another example is photo tagging.
‎另一个例子是照片圈人
So, if you get an e  mail
‎如果你收到一封邮件 ‎
that says your friend just tagged you in a photo,
说你朋友刚刚在一张照片中圈出了你
of course you're going to click on that e  mail and look at the photo.
‎你当然会点击那封邮件 看一下照片
It's not something you can just decide to ignore.
‎这不是你能选择忽略的事情
This is deep  seated, like,
‎他们所利用的 ‎
human personality that they're tapping into.
是根植于人类本性中的东西
What you should be asking yourself is:
‎你应该问自己的是
"Why doesn't that e  mail contain the photo in it?
‎“这封邮件中 ‎为什么没把照片放进来？
It would be a lot easier to see the photo."
‎这样 看照片就会容易很多 ”
When Facebook found that feature, they just dialed the hell out of that
‎当脸书发现这个功能之后 ‎他们可真是尽情调控
because they said, "This is gonna be a great way to grow activity.
‎因为他们说 ‎“这将是增长积极性的绝好方式
Let's just get people tagging each other in photos all day long."
‎我们让大家整天在照片中互相圈吧”
‎（本：至少我们中 ‎有一个人拍得很好）
He commented.
‎他评论了
Nice.
‎很好
Okay, Rebecca received it, and she is responding.
‎瑞贝卡收到了 她正在回复
All right, let Ben know that she's typing so we don't lose him.
‎好 让本知道她在输入 别让他下线了
Activating ellipsis.
‎激活省略号
‎（至少我们中有一个人拍得很好 ‎…）
Great, she posted.
‎太好了 她发布了
He's commenting on her comment about his comment on her post.
‎他在评论 他给她发帖的评论的评论
Hold on, he stopped typing.
‎等一下 他停止输入了
Let's autofill.
‎我们来自动填入
Emojis. He loves emojis.
‎表情 他喜欢使用表情
‎（自动完成 参与度）
He went with fire.
‎他选择了“火辣”表情
I was rootin' for eggplant.
‎我以为他会选择茄子呢
There's an entire discipline and field called "growth hacking."
‎有一整个学科 ‎这个领域叫做“增长量黑客学”
Teams of engineers whose job is to hack people's psychology
‎无数工程师团队 ‎他们的工作就是黑入人们的心理
so they can get more growth.
‎让他们拥有更多的增长量
They can get more user sign  ups, more engagement.
‎他们能得到更多的用户注册 ‎更高的参与度
They can get you to invite more people.
‎能让你邀请更多人
After all the testing, all the iterating, all of this stuff,
‎各种测试、迭代 种种操作之后
you know the single biggest thing we realized?
‎知道我们发现最重要现象是什么吗？
Get any individual to seven friends in ten days.
‎让任何个体在十天内邀请七个朋友
‎（查马斯·帕里哈皮提亚 ‎脸书前增长副总裁）
That was it.
‎就是这个
Chamath was the head of growth at Facebook early on,
‎查马斯是脸书早期的增长负责人
and he's very well known in the tech industry
‎他在技术领域非常知名
for pioneering a lot of the growth tactics
‎因为他首创了很多增长手段
that were used to grow Facebook at incredible speed.
‎这些手段的使用 ‎让脸书用户飞速增长
And those growth tactics have then become the standard playbook for Silicon Valley.
‎后来那些增长手段 ‎变成了硅谷的标准战术
They were used at Uber and at a bunch of other companies.
‎在优步使用了 ‎在很多其他公司也使用了
One of the things that he pioneered was the use of scientific A/B testing
‎他首创的一个东西 ‎就是对功能上的小变化
of small feature changes.
‎使用科学A/B测试
Companies like Google and Facebook
‎谷歌和脸书这种公司
would roll out lots of little, tiny experiments
‎会推出很多小实验
that they were constantly doing on users.
‎他们不断在用户身上测试
And over time, by running these constant experiments,
‎随着时间发展 ‎不停运行这些实验之后
you... you develop the most optimal way
‎就能发展出能让用户 ‎做你想让他们做的事
to get users to do what you want them to do.
‎的最佳方式
It's... It's manipulation.
‎这就是操纵
Uh, you're making me feel like a lab rat.
‎你让我感觉自己像是实验室的小白鼠
You are a lab rat. We're all lab rats.
‎你就是实验室的小白鼠 ‎我们所有人都是
And it's not like we're lab rats for developing a cure for cancer.
‎我们和开发治愈癌症药物的 ‎实验室小白鼠又不一样
It's not like they're trying to benefit us.
‎这些实验的最终获益人 不是我们
Right?  We're just zombies, and they want us to look at more ads
‎对吧？我们就像僵尸一样 ‎他们想让我们看更多的广告
so they can make more  money.
‎让他们挣更多的钱
Facebook conducted
‎脸书做了一个实验 ‎
what they called "massive  scale contagion experiments."
他们称为“海量规模蔓延实验”
Okay.
‎好吧
How do we use subliminal cues on the Facebook pages
‎我们怎样用脸书页面上的潜意识信号
to get more people to go vote in the midterm elections?
‎来让更多人在中期选举中投票？
And they discovered that they were able to do that.
‎他们发现 他们能做到
One thing they concluded is that we now know
‎他们得出的一个结论是 ‎现在我们知道
we can affect real  world behavior and emotions
‎我们能影响现实世界中的行为和情感
without ever triggering the user's awareness.
‎而根本不用触发用户的意识
They are completely clueless.
‎他们自己完全不知道
We're pointing these engines of AI back at ourselves
‎我们将这些人工智能引擎 ‎指回到我们身上
to reverse  engineer what elicits responses from us.
‎来反向编程 什么能引诱我们的回应
Almost like you're stimulating nerve cells on a spider
‎就很像你在蜘蛛身上模拟神经细胞
to see what causes its legs to respond.
‎来看是什么引起它的腿反应
So, it really is this kind of prison experiment
‎就是这种监狱实验
where we're just, you know, roping people into the matrix,
‎我们在实验中 捆绑人们进入矩阵
and we're just harvesting all this money and... and data from all their activity
‎我们从他们的行为中获取金钱和数据 ‎
to profit from.
用他们的行为牟利
And we're not even aware that it's happening.
‎我们甚至都不知道 发生了这些
So, we want to psychologically figure out how to manipulate you as fast as possible
‎我们想在心理学上弄清楚 ‎怎样以最快的速度操纵你
and then give you back that dopamine hit.
‎然后返回给你让你产生兴奋的事物
We did that brilliantly at Facebook.
‎我们在脸书做得非常出色
Instagram has done it. WhatsApp has done it.
‎Instagram也这样做了 ‎WhatsApp也这样做了
You know, Snapchat has done it. Twitter has done it.
‎阅后即焚图片分享也这样做了 ‎推特也这样做了
I mean, it's exactly the kind of thing
‎这种东西正是
that a... that a hacker like myself would come up with
‎我这种黑客能想出来的
because you're exploiting a vulnerability in... in human psychology.
‎因为你在利用人类心理中的脆弱挣钱
‎（希恩·帕克 脸书前总经理）
And I just... I think that we...
‎我只是想
you know, the inventors, creators...
我们这些发明者、创造者…
uh, you know, and it's me, it's Mark, it's the...
‎有我 有马克 有…
you know, Kevin Systrom at Instagram... It's all of these people...
‎Instagram的凯文·斯特罗姆 ‎所有这些人…
um, understood this consciously, and we did it anyway.
‎意识里非常清楚 但我们依然利用了
No one got upset when bicycles showed up.
‎自行车问世的时候 没有人不满
Right?  Like, if everyone's starting to go around on bicycles,
‎对吧？所有人都开始用自行车出行
no one said, "Oh, my God, we've just ruined society.
‎没有人说 ‎“天啊 我们刚刚毁掉了社会
Like, bicycles are affecting people.
‎因为自行车能影响人
They're pulling people away from their kids.
‎拉远了他们和孩子间的距离
They're ruining the fabric of democracy. People can't tell what's true."
‎他们在毁掉民主的结构 ‎人们无法判断真假了”
Like, we never said any of that stuff about a bicycle.
‎对于自行车 ‎我们从来没有说过这种话
If something is a tool, it genuinely is just sitting there,
‎如果一个东西是工具 ‎它就会忠诚地坐在那里
waiting patiently.
‎耐心等待
If something is not a tool, it's demanding things from you.
‎如果一个东西不是工具 ‎它会在你身上有所求
It's seducing you. It's manipulating you. It wants things from you.
‎引诱你、操纵你 想从你身上获利
And we've moved away from having a tools  based technology environment
‎我们已经走过了 ‎以工具为基础的技术环境
to an addiction   and manipulation  based technology environment.
‎来到了以致瘾和操纵 ‎为基础的技术环境
That's what's changed.
‎这是技术环境的改变
Social media isn't a tool that's just waiting to be used.
‎社交媒体 ‎不是原地等在那里被使用的工具
It has its own goals, and it has its own means of pursuing them
‎它有自己的目标 ‎有自己的办法去实现这些目标
by using your psychology against you.
‎利用你的心理 来对付你
‎（“只有两个行业 ‎把他们的客户叫做‘使用者’
‎非法毒品和软件”）
‎（——爱德华·塔夫特）
Rewind a few years ago, I was the...
‎回想几年之前
I was the president of Pinterest.
‎我是Pinterest的总经理
I was coming home,
‎我回到家
and I couldn't get off my phone once I got home,
到家之后就无法放下手机
despite having two young kids who needed my love and attention.
‎虽然我有两个小孩子 需要我的关爱
I was in the pantry, you know, typing away on an e  mail
‎我在食物储藏室里打字回邮件
or sometimes looking at Pinterest.
‎有时候会看Pinterest
I thought, "God, this is classic irony.
‎我想：“天啊 这真是典型的讽刺
I am going to work during the day
‎我白天去工作
and building something that then I am falling prey to."
‎构造一个把我当猎物的东西”
And I couldn't... I mean, some of those moments, I couldn't help myself.
‎我无法… 有时候 ‎我真的情不自禁使用
The one that I'm... I'm most prone to is Twitter.
‎我最无法摆脱的是推特
Uh, used to be Reddit.
‎以前无法摆脱的是Reddit
I actually had to write myself software to break my addiction to reading Reddit.
‎我后来不得不给自己写程序 ‎来切断我阅读Reddit的瘾
I'm probably most addicted to my e  mail.
‎我最成瘾的 可能是邮件
I mean, really. I mean, I... I feel it.
‎真的 我是认真的 我自己能感觉到
Well, I mean, it's sort     it's interesting
‎这很有趣
that knowing what was going on behind the curtain,
‎我很清楚 这一切的幕后发生着什么
I still wasn't able to control my usage.
‎我还是无法控制自己去使用
So, that's a little scary.
‎这就有点可怕了
Even knowing how these tricks work, I'm still susceptible to them.
‎即便知道这些手段的原理 ‎我还是容易受到它们影响
I'll still pick up the phone, and 20 minutes will disappear.
‎我拿起手机 ‎20分钟就不知不觉过去了
Do you check your smartphone before you pee in the morning
‎你晨起排尿之前 ‎会看一眼智能手机吗？
or while you're peeing in the morning?
‎或者晨起排尿过程中 会看吗？
'Cause those are the only two choices.
‎因为只有这两个选择
I tried through willpower, just pure willpower...
‎我试过用意志力克制 纯意志力…
"I'll put down my phone, I'll leave my phone in the car when I get home."
‎“我要放下手机 ‎我到家之后 要把手机丢在车里”
I think I told myself a thousand times, a thousand different days,
‎我应该在千万个不同的日子 ‎告诉过自己千万次
"I am not gonna bring my phone to the bedroom,"
‎“我不要把手机带到卧室”
and then 9:00 p.m. rolls around.
‎然后晚上九点到了
"Well, I wanna bring my phone in the bedroom."
‎“哎 我想把手机带进卧室”
And so, that was sort of...
‎这就有点…
Willpower was kind of attempt one,
‎意志力是一种努力
and then attempt two was, you know, brute force.
‎兽性在做着另一种努力
Introducing the Kitchen Safe. The Kitchen Safe is a revolutionary,
‎隆重介绍“厨房保险箱”  ‎“厨房保险箱”
new, time  locking container that helps you fight temptation.
是革命性的全新发明 ‎帮你战胜诱惑的 ‎时间锁保鲜盒
All David has to do is place those temptations in the Kitchen Safe.
‎大卫只需要把各种诱惑 ‎放进这个“厨房保险箱”
Next, he rotates the dial to set the timer.
‎下一步 进行调控 设置时间
And, finally, he presses the dial to activate the lock.
‎最后 按下调控 激活锁
The Kitchen Safe is great...
‎“厨房保险箱”超级好
We have that, don't we?
‎我们家有 是吧？
...video games, credit cards, and cell phones.
‎…电子游戏、信用卡、手机
Yeah, we do.
‎对 有
Once the Kitchen Safe is locked, it cannot be opened
‎“厨房保险箱”一旦上锁 ‎直到计时器归零之前
until the timer reaches zero.
没办法打开
So, here's the thing.
‎问题是
Social media is a drug.
社交媒体就是一种毒品
I mean, we have a basic biological imperative
‎我们有着基本的生物学欲望
to connect with other people.
‎去和别人联系
That directly affects the release of dopamine in the reward pathway.
‎这直接影响着 ‎奖赏通路中的多巴胺释放
Millions of years of evolution, um, are behind that system
‎这个机制背后 是几百万年的进化
to get us to come together and live in communities,
‎让我们聚在一起 群居生活
to find mates, to propagate our species.
‎找到伴侣 繁殖我们的物种
So, there's no doubt that a vehicle like social media,
‎所以 毫无疑问 社交媒体这种载体
which optimizes this connection between people,
‎它会优化人们之间的联系
is going to have the potential for addiction.
‎自然会有致瘾的可能性
Mmm!      Dad, stop!
‎爸 停！
I have, like, 1,000 more snips to send before dinner.
‎我在晚饭前 还有上千个消息要回
Snips?    I don't know what a snip is.
‎消息？
‎我不知道消息是什么
Mm, that smells good, baby.   All right. Thank you.
‎  闻起来好香 宝贝 ‎  谢谢
I was, um, thinking we could use all five senses
‎我想 我们可以用所有五官
to enjoy our dinner tonight.
‎来享受今晚的晚餐
So, I decided that we're not gonna have any cell phones at the table tonight.
‎所以我决定 ‎今晚的餐桌上不能使用手机
So, turn 'em in.
‎好了 交上来
Really?       Yep.
‎  真的吗？ ‎  是
All right.   Thank you. Ben?
‎  好吧 ‎  谢谢 本？
Okay.   Mom, the phone pirate.
‎  好 ‎  妈妈是手机海盗
Got it.   Mom!
‎  拿走了 ‎  妈！
So, they will be safe in here until after dinner...
‎晚餐结束前 ‎这些手机会安全地放在这里
and everyone can just chill out.
‎所有人可以安静待着了
Okay?
好吗？
Can I just see who it is?    No.
‎  我能看一眼是谁吗？ ‎  不行
Just gonna go get another fork.
‎我去再拿一个叉子
Thank you.
‎谢谢
Honey, you can't open that.
‎宝贝 不能打开
I locked it for an hour, so just leave it alone.
‎我锁上了一个小时 别动了
So, what should we talk about?
‎我们要聊点什么？
Well, we could talk
‎我们可以聊聊
about the, uh, Extreme Center wackos I drove by today.
我今天开车 ‎身边经过的极端中心政党疯子
Please, Frank.   What?
‎  算了 弗兰科 ‎  怎么了？
I don't wanna talk about politics.
‎我不想聊政治
What's wrong with the Extreme Center?    See?  He doesn't even get it.
‎  极端中心怎么了？ ‎  看吧？他都没明白
It depends on who you ask.
‎取决于你问谁
It's like asking, "What's wrong with propaganda? "
‎这就像是你问：“政治鼓吹怎么了？”
Isla!
‎艾拉！
Oh, my God.
‎天啊
Do you want me to...      Yeah.
‎  需要我去… ‎  嗯
I... I'm worried about my kids.
‎我很担心我的孩子们
And if you have kids, I'm worried about your kids.
‎等你们有了孩子 ‎我还会担心你们的孩子
Armed with all the knowledge that I have and all of the experience,
‎虽然我有着各种知识储备 各种经验
I am fighting my kids about the time
‎我还是和孩子们争论
that they spend on phones and on the computer.
‎他们使用手机和电脑的时间
I will say to my son, "How many hours do you think you're spending on your phone? "
‎我会对我儿子说 ‎“你觉得自己会在手机上花多久？”
He'll be like, "It's, like, half an hour. It's half an hour, tops."
‎他会说 ‎“也就半小时吧 最多半小时了”
I'd say upwards hour, hour and a half.
‎我觉得比一小时多一点 一个半小时
I looked at his screen report a couple weeks ago.
‎几周之前看了他的屏幕使用报告
Three hours and 45 minutes.      That...
‎  是3小时45分 ‎  那不是…
I don't think that's... No. Per day, on average?
‎我觉得没有… 平均每天？
Yeah.   Should I go get it right now?
‎  对 ‎  我现在去拿来吗？
There's not a day that goes by that I don't remind my kids
‎每一天 我都要提醒我的孩子们
about the pleasure  pain balance,
‎愉悦和痛苦的平衡
about dopamine deficit states,
‎多巴胺短缺的状态
about the risk of addiction.
上瘾的风险
Moment of truth.
‎  对 ‎  来揭晓真相
Two hours, 50 minutes per day.
‎每天2小时50分
Let's see.   Actually, I've been using a lot today.
‎  我们看看 ‎  其实 我今天用了很多
Last seven days.   That's probably why.
‎  过去七天 ‎  可能这就是原因
Instagram, six hours, 13 minutes. Okay, so my Instagram's worse.
‎Instagram 6小时13分 ‎好吧 我使用Instagram是最严重的
My screen's completely shattered.
‎我的屏幕彻底碎了
Thanks, Cass.
谢谢你 卡桑
What do you mean, "Thanks, Cass"?
‎“谢谢你 卡桑”是什么意思？
You keep freaking Mom out about our phones when it's not really a problem.
‎你一直让妈妈担心我们的手机问题 ‎但其实这根本不是问题
We don't need our phones to eat dinner!
‎我们吃晚餐不需要手机
I get what you're saying. It's just not that big a deal. It's not.
‎我明白你说的 ‎但这又不是什么大事 没什么啊
If it's not that big a deal, don't use it for a week.
‎不是什么大事 那就一周别用手机
Yeah. Yeah, actually, if you can put that thing away for, like, a whole week...
‎对 ‎对 其实 如果你能把那东西 ‎收起来一整周…
I will buy you a new screen.
‎我就给你买一个新的屏幕
Like, starting now?       Starting now.
‎  从现在开始吗？ ‎  现在开始
Okay. You got a deal.      Okay.
‎好 成交
Okay, you gotta leave it here, though, buddy.
‎好 不过你要放在这里 小朋友
All right, I'm plugging it in.
‎好 我把它放进去
Let the record show... I'm backing away.
‎计时开始 我退后了
Okay.
‎好
You're on the clock.      One week.
‎  计时开始了 ‎  一周
Oh, my...
‎天啊…
Think he can do it?
‎你觉得他能做到吗？
I don't know. We'll see.
‎不知道 走着瞧
Just eat, okay?
‎你吃饭吧 好吗？
Good family dinner!
‎美好的家庭晚餐！
These technology products were not designed
‎这些技术产品不是由
by child psychologists who are trying to protect and nurture children.
‎努力保护和培育孩子的 ‎儿童心理学家设计的
They were just designing to make these algorithms
‎它们的设计 是让这些算法
that were really good at recommending the next video to you
‎非常擅于给你推荐下一个视频
or really good at getting you to take a photo with a filter on it.
‎非常擅于让你拍照加滤镜
‎（两个赞）
‎（确定删除吗？否）
‎（是）
It's not just that it's controlling
‎这些东西不仅在控制 ‎
where they spend their attention.
他们把注意力花在哪里
Especially social media starts to dig deeper and deeper down into the brain stem
‎尤其是社交媒体越来越深入大脑根部
and take over kids' sense of self  worth and identity.
‎夺走孩子们的判断力 ‎自我价值和身份
‎（美化我）
‎（莉莉：可爱！）
‎（索薇娅：天啊 好美）
‎（奥利维亚：你太美了）
‎（阿瓦：你把耳朵P大了吗？）
‎（哈哈）
We evolved to care about whether other people in our tribe...
‎我们进化出 ‎在意我们社群中的其他人…
‎（布里亚纳：漂亮！）
think well of us or not 'cause it matters.
‎…是否对我们有好印象的机制 ‎因为这很重要
But were we evolved to be aware of what 10,000 people think of us?
‎但我们的进化 需要我们在意 ‎一万个人怎么看我们吗？
We were not evolved to have social approval being dosed to us
‎我们的进化 ‎不需要每隔五分钟
every five minutes.
‎就获得一次社交认可
That was not at all what we were built to experience.
‎这根本不是我们需要去体验的
We curate our lives around this perceived sense of perfection
‎我们管理自己的生活 ‎建立在获得的完美感上
because we get rewarded in these short  term signals
‎因为爱心、点赞、竖起大拇指 ‎这些短期的信号
hearts, likes, thumbs  up
‎给我们奖赏
and we conflate that with value, and we conflate it with truth.
‎我们把它融合到价值中 ‎融合到真相中
And instead, what it really is is fake, brittle popularity...
‎不论是否虚假 易破碎的人气
that's short  term and that leaves you even more, and admit it,
‎这是短期的 你需要承认 这让你更加
vacant and empty before you did it.
‎空虚 于是会再次这样做
Because then it forces you into this vicious cycle
‎因为这样 ‎它会将你逼入这样一个恶性循环
where you're like, "What's the next thing I need to do now?   'Cause I need it back."
‎你会想：“我接下来要做什么？ ‎因为我还想要这种感觉”
Think about that compounded by two billion people,
‎想一下 这种现象被20亿人复杂化
and then think about how people react then to the perceptions of others.
‎然后想一下 之后人们 ‎会怎样回应别人对自己的看法
It's just a... It's really bad.
‎真的… 真的很恶劣
It's really, really bad.
‎真的太恶劣了
There has been a gigantic increase
‎美国青少年群体中
in depression and anxiety for American teenagers
‎出现了大幅增长的抑郁和焦虑
which began right around... between 2011 and 2013.
‎大概就在2011年到2013年开始的
The number of teenage girls out of 100,000 in this country
‎这个国家中 每十万名少女中
who were admitted to a hospital every year
‎每年因为割腕或者自残
because they cut themselves or otherwise harmed themselves,
‎进医院接受治疗的人数
that number was pretty stable until around 2010, 2011,
‎在2010年到2011年是非常平稳的
and then it begins going way up.
‎在那之后 直线上升
It's up 62 percent for older teen girls.
‎大一点的少女中 增加了62%
‎（美国非致命性自残住院人数）
It's up 189 percent for the preteen girls. That's nearly triple.
‎进入青春期前的少女 增加了189% ‎将近三倍了
Even more horrifying, we see the same pattern with suicide.
‎更可怕的是 ‎自杀也呈现出相同的趋势
‎（美国自杀率 ‎每百万女孩死亡人数）
The older teen girls, 15 to 19 years old,
‎大一点的少女 15到19岁
they're up 70 percent,compared to the first decade of this century.
‎与本世纪初相比 增长了70%
The preteen girls, who have very low rates to begin with,
‎青春期前的少女 ‎最开始的比率非常低
they are up 151 percent.
‎现在增长了151%
And that pattern points to social media.
‎这个增长模式 指向了社交媒体
‎（2009年手机上的社交媒体数量）
Gen Z, the kids born after 1996 or so,
‎Z代人 ‎1996年之后那会儿出生的孩子们
those kids are the first generation in history
‎那些孩子们是历史上第一代
that got on social media in middle school.
‎在初中开始使用社交媒体的
How do they spend their time?
‎她们的时间花在了哪里呢？
They come home from school, and they're on their devices.
‎她们放学回家 就拿起手机
A whole generation is more anxious, more fragile, more depressed.
‎整个一代人都更加焦虑 ‎更加脆弱、更加抑郁
They're much less comfortable taking risks.
她们更不愿意冒险
The rates at which they get driver's licenses have been dropping.
‎她们拿到驾照的比率下降了
The number who have ever gone out on a date
‎出去约会过的人数
or had any kind of romantic interaction is dropping rapidly.
‎有过任何形式浪漫互动的人数骤减
This is a real change in a generation.
‎整个一代人 有了真正的改变
And remember, for every one of these, for every hospital admission,
‎别忘了 这些人中的每一个 ‎每一个住院的人
there's a family that is traumatized and horrified.
‎背后都有一个受伤的、惊恐的家庭
"My God, what is happening to our kids? "
‎“天啊 我的孩子们怎么了？”
It's plain as day to me.
‎在我看来 问题很显而易见
These services are killing people... and causing people to kill themselves.
‎这些服务正在杀人 ‎也在导致人们自杀
I don't know any parent who says, "Yeah, I really want my kids to be growing up
‎我不认识哪个家长会说 ‎“是 我希望我的孩子们 成长过程中
feeling manipulated by tech designers, uh,
‎感觉被技术设计师操控
manipulating their attention, making it impossible to do their homework,
‎操控他们的注意力 ‎让他们无法完成作业
making them compare themselves to unrealistic standards of beauty."
‎让他们将自己 ‎和不切实际的审美标准相对比”
Like, no one wants that.
‎没有人希望那样
No one does.
‎没有一个人
We... We used to have these protections.
‎我们以前有一些保护措施
When children watched Saturday morning cartoons,
‎小孩子们观看周六早间动画片的时候
we cared about protecting children.
‎我们关心保护儿童
We would say, "You can't advertise to these age children in these ways."
‎我们会说：“你不能这样 ‎给这个年龄段的孩子看广告”
But then you take YouTube for Kids,
‎然后有了YouTube儿童频道
and it gobbles up that entire portion of the attention economy,
‎蚕食了注意力经济的全部
and now all kids are exposed to YouTube for Kids.
‎现在所有的孩子 ‎都能看YouTube儿童频道
And all those protections and all those regulations are gone.
‎所有的保护措施 ‎所有的管理规定都不见了
We're training and conditioning a whole new generation of people...
‎我们在训练、调节整个一代人…
that when we are uncomfortable or lonely or uncertain or afraid,
‎我们不自在、孤独、不确定或害怕时
we have a digital pacifier for ourselves
‎有一个自己的数码安慰
that is kind of atrophying our own ability to deal with that.
‎这有点让我们 ‎自己处理这些情绪的能力退化了
Photoshop didn't have 1,000 engineers
‎Photoshop屏幕的另一端 ‎
on the other side of the screen, using notifications, using your friends,
‎没有几千个工程师 用通知 用你的朋友
using AI to predict what's gonna perfectly addict you, or hook you,
‎用人工智能去预判 ‎什么能完美地让你上瘾 引诱你
or manipulate you, or allow advertisers
‎或者操纵你 或者允许广告商
to test 60,000 variations of text or colors to figure out
‎去测试六万种不同的文本或颜色
‎（芝加哥反垄断技术会议）
what's the perfect manipulation of your mind.
‎…以此来找到 ‎怎样能完美地操纵你的思想
This is a totally new species of power and influence.
‎这是一种全新的力量和影响
I... I would say, again, the methods used
‎我想再一次强调 他们使用的
to play on people's ability to be addicted or to be influenced
‎玩弄人们的能力 ‎让人们成瘾或者受到影响
may be different this time, and they probably are different.
‎或许这一次是不同的 ‎或许他们是不同的
They were different when newspapers came in and the printing press came in,
‎报纸问世时 印刷媒体问世时 ‎与现在很不同
and they were different when television came in,
‎电视问世的时候 与现在很不同
and you had three major networks and...
‎当时有三个主要的…‎  网络
At the time.   At the time. That's what I'm saying.
‎  当时 我也想说
But I'm saying the idea that there's a new level
‎但我在说 这是一个全新的层次
and that new level has happened so many times before.
‎这个新的层次 以前也发生过很多次
I mean, this is just the latest new level that we've seen.
‎这只是我们看见的 最新的一个层次
There's this narrative that, you know, "We'll just adapt to it.
‎有这样一种说法：“我们去适应它
We'll learn how to live with these devices,
‎我们要学着与这些设备共存
just like we've learned how to live with everything else."
‎就像我们学着 ‎和其他所有事物共存一样”
And what this misses is there's something distinctly new here.
‎但这个说法没有注意到的是 ‎有些东西明显是全新的
Perhaps the most dangerous piece of all this is the fact
‎或许这其中最危险的是
that it's driven by technology that's advancing exponentially.
‎这是由技术驱动的 ‎在成指数地向前发展
‎（计算机处理能力）
Roughly, if you say from, like, the 1960s to today,
‎大体上 ‎如果你看从20世纪60年代至今
processing power has gone up about a trillion times.
‎计算机处理能力增长了万亿倍
Nothing else that we have has improved at anything near that rate.
‎我们身边没有任何其他东西 ‎以这个速率增长
Like, cars are, you know, roughly twice as fast.
‎比如 汽车速度基本上才实现翻倍
And almost everything else is negligible.
‎几乎所有其他的东西都显得微不足道
And perhaps most importantly,
‎或许最重要的是
our human     our physiology, our brains have evolved not at all.
‎我们人类… 我们的生理 ‎我们的大脑 根本没有丝毫进化
‎（没有手机的时间）
Human beings, at a mind and body and sort of physical level,
‎人类的思想、身体和体质
are not gonna fundamentally change.
‎基本上不会改变了
I know, but they...
We can do genetic engineering and develop new kinds of human beings,
‎我们可以搞基因工程 ‎在未来开发新的人类物种
but realistically speaking, you're living inside of hardware, a brain,
‎但是现实来讲 ‎你生活在大脑这个硬件下
that was, like, millions of years old,
‎已经存在几百万年了
and then there's this screen, and then on the opposite side of the screen,
‎然后出现了这样一个屏幕 ‎在屏幕的另一端
there's these thousands of engineers and supercomputers
‎有上千名工程师和超级计算机
that have goals that are different than your goals,
‎有着与你不同的目标
and so, who's gonna win in that game?  Who's gonna win?
‎那么 这个游戏谁能赢呢？谁会赢？
How are we losing?
‎我们怎么会输？
I don't know.   Where is he?  This is not normal.
‎  我不知道 ‎  他在哪里？这太不正常了
Did I overwhelm him with friends and family content?
‎我给他推送朋友和家人的内容太多 ‎他烦了吗？
Probably.   Well, maybe it was all the ads.
‎  或许吧 ‎  或许是广告太多了
No. Something's very wrong. Let's switch to resurrection mode.
‎不 一定出了严重的问题 ‎我们切换到复苏模式吧
When you think of AI, you know, an AI's gonna ruin the world,
‎当你想到人工智能 ‎人工智能会毁掉世界
and you see, like, a Terminator, and you see Arnold Schwarzenegger.
‎你会看到《终结者》 看到施瓦辛格…
I'll be back.
‎我会回来的
You see drones, and you think, like,
‎…你会看到无人机 你觉得 ‎
"Oh, we're gonna kill people with AI."
“人工智能会杀人的”
And what people miss is that AI already runs today's world right now.
‎人们忽略的是 人工智能 ‎现在已经在运营着当今世界了
Even talking about "an AI" is just a metaphor.
‎甚至谈论“人工智能”都只是暗喻
At these companies like... like Google, there's just massive, massive rooms,
‎在谷歌这种公司 有超级大的房间
some of them underground, some of them underwater,
‎有些在地下 有些在水下
of just computers.
‎房间里全是电脑
Tons and tons of computers, as far as the eye can see.
‎无数的电脑 连绵不绝
They're deeply interconnected with each other
‎它们互相之间在内部深度连接
and running extremely complicated programs,
‎在运行着极其复杂的程序
sending information back and forth between each other all the time.
‎始终不停地在彼此之间交换信息
And they'll be running many different programs,
它们会运行很多不同的程序
many different products on those same machines.
‎在同样的机器上 有不同的产品
Some of those things could be described as simple algorithms,
‎有些东西可以被描述为简单算法
some could be described as algorithms
‎有些算法太过复杂
that are so complicated, you would call them intelligence.
‎就可以被称为“智能”
I like to say that algorithms are opinions embedded in code...
‎我想说 算法是内嵌在代码中的观点…
and that algorithms are not objective.
‎算法并不是客观的
Algorithms are optimized to some definition of success.
‎算法被某种成功的定义优化
So, if you can imagine,
‎所以 如果你能想象
if a... if a commercial enterprise builds an algorithm
‎一个商业公司成功的定义
to their definition of success,
‎需要依靠算法
it's a commercial interest.
‎那就是商业利益
It's usually profit.
‎通常都有利润
You are giving the computer the goal state, "I want this outcome,"
‎你给电脑一个目标 ‎说“我想要这个结果”
and then the computer itself is learning how to do it.
‎电脑自己去学习 怎样实现
That's where the term "machine learning" comes from.
‎这是“机器学习”概念的由来
And so, every day, it gets slightly better
‎所以 每一天 都会更好一点
at picking the right posts in the right order
‎在正确命令获取正确的推送数据
so that you spend longer and longer in that product.
‎让你在这个产品上花的时间越来越多
And no one really understands what they're doing
‎没人能真正明白 为了实现这个目标
in order to achieve that goal.
‎他们在做什么
The algorithm has a mind of its own, so even though a person writes it,
‎算法有着自己的思想 虽然是人写的
it's written in a way
‎它写出来的目的
that you kind of build the machine, and then the machine changes itself.
‎是你建立一个机器 ‎这个机器会自己改变
There's only a handful of people at these companies,
‎这种公司 员工非常少
at Facebook and Twitter and other companies...
‎在脸书、推特和其他公司
There's only a few people who understand how those systems work,
‎只有几个人能明白 ‎这些系统的工作原理
and even they don't necessarily fully understand
‎虽然他们不需要完全理解
what's gonna happen with a particular piece of content.
‎某一条特定的内容 会发生什么
So, as humans, we've almost lost control over these systems.
‎作为人类 我们几乎 ‎已经失去了对这些系统的控制
Because they're controlling, you know, the information that we see,
‎因为是它们在控制我们看到的信息
they're controlling us more than we're controlling them.
‎更多的是它们在控制我们 ‎而不是我们控制它们
Cross  referencing him
‎在他的地理区域
against comparables in his geographic zone.
对他和可以对比的人 ‎进行交叉参照
His psychometric  doppelgangers.
‎他的心理测定相似者
There are 13,694 people behaving just like him in his region.
‎在他的地区 ‎有13694个和他行为相似的人
What's trending with them?    We need something actually good
‎  他们中盛行什么？ ‎  我们需要真实的好东西
for a proper resurrection,
‎才能进行有效的复苏
given that the typical stuff isn't working.
‎因为平常的那些东西已经不起作用了
Not even that cute girl from school.
‎学校那个可爱的姑娘都没用了
My analysis shows that going political with Extreme Center content
‎我的分析显示 ‎用极端中心内容搞政治
has a 62.3 percent chance of long  term engagement.
‎有62.3%的几率能够获得长期参与
That's not bad.
‎还不错
It's not good enough to lead with.
‎想用它引导 还不太够
Okay, okay, so we've tried notifying him about tagged photos,
‎好 所以我们已经试过 ‎通知给他圈人照片
invitations, current events, even a direct message from  Rebecca.
‎邀请、实事、甚至是瑞贝卡的私信
But what about User 01265923010?
‎但是用户01265923010呢？
Yeah, Ben loved all of her posts.
‎是 本点赞了她所有的发帖
For months and, like, literally all of them, and then nothing.
‎几个月的所有发帖 真的点了所有 ‎然后就没有然后了
I calculate a 92.3 percent chance of resurrection
‎我算出了通知安娜的内容
with a notification about Ana.
‎会有92.3%的复苏概率
‎（新感情）
And her new friend.
‎还有她的新朋友
‎（没有手机的时间）
‎（你的前女友有了新感情！）
Oh, you gotta be kiddin' me.
‎不是吧
Okay.
‎好吧
‎（安娜与路易斯正在热恋）
What?
‎什么？
Bam! We're back!
‎当！我们回来了！
Let's get back to making money, boys.
‎我们继续挣钱 兄弟们
Yes, and connecting Ben with the entire world.
‎好 让他们和整个世界联系起来
I'm giving him access to all the information he might like.
‎我给他看所有他可能喜欢的信息
Hey, do you guys ever wonder if, you know, like, the feed is good for Ben?
‎你们是否想过 ‎这些推送对本是好的吗？
No.   No.
‎  没想过 ‎  没有
I put a spell on you
‎我在你身上下了咒语
'Cause you're mine
‎因为你是我的
You better stop the things you do
‎你最好停止你做的事情
I ain't lyin'
‎我不骗你
‎（A/B测试 极端中心）
No, I ain't lyin'
‎不 我不骗你
You know I can't stand it
‎你知道我无法忍受
You're runnin' around
‎你在四处奔跑
You know better, Daddy
‎爸爸 你更清楚
I can't stand it 'Cause you put me down
‎我无法忍受 因为你将我放下
Yeah, yeah
‎耶
I put a spell on you
‎我在你身上下了咒语
Because you're mine
‎因为你是我的
You're mine
‎你是我的
So, imagine you're on Facebook...
‎想象一下 你在用脸书…
and you're effectively playing against this artificial intelligence
‎你的对手是人工智能
that knows everything about you,
‎它知道你的一切
can anticipate your next move, and you know literally nothing about it,
‎能够预测你未来的举动 ‎你对它却一无所知
except that there are cat videos and birthdays on it.
‎除了上面有猫的视频和出生日期
That's not a fair fight.
‎这根本不是公平的竞争
Ben and Jerry, it's time to go, bud!
‎本与杰瑞 该走了 孩子？
Ben?
‎本？
Ben.      Mm.
‎本
Come on.
‎快点
School time.
‎该上学了
Let's go.
我们走
‎（人道技术中心）
How you doing today?    Oh, I'm... I'm nervous.
‎  你今天怎么样？ ‎  我很紧张
Are ya?    Yeah.
‎  你紧张吗？ ‎  是啊
We were all looking for the moment
‎我们都在当心这个时刻
when technology would overwhelm human strengths and intelligence.
‎当技术会超越人类力量和智慧
When is it gonna cross the singularity, replace our jobs, be smarter than humans?
‎技术什么时候会超越人类 ‎取代我们的工作 比人类更聪明？
But there's this much earlier moment...
‎但有更早的时刻…
when technology exceeds and overwhelms human weaknesses.
‎技术超越人类的弱点时
This point being crossed is at the root of addiction,
‎这个超越的点就是上瘾
polarization, radicalization, outrage  ification,
‎两极分化、激进化、激化愤怒
vanity  ification, the entire thing.
‎激化虚荣 一切的根源
This is overpowering human nature,
‎它在压制人类天性
and this is checkmate on humanity.
‎在挫伤人性
I'm sorry.
‎很抱歉
One of the ways I try to get people to understand
‎我努力让人们明白
just how wrong feeds from places like Facebook are
‎脸书这种地方的推送 ‎有多错误的一种方式
is to think about the Wikipedia.
‎是让他们去想想维基百科
‎（新标签页）
When you go to a page, you're seeing the same thing as other people.
‎当你打开一个维基百科网页 ‎你和别人看到的东西是一样的
‎（维基百科 自由的百科全书）
So, it's one of the few things online that we at least hold in common.
‎所以 这是网络上少有的 ‎我们统一共享的东西
Now, just imagine for a second that Wikipedia said,
‎现在 现象一下 维基百科说
"We're gonna give each person a different customized definition,
‎我们要给每一个人不同的个性化定义
and we're gonna be paid by people for that."
‎有人给我们钱 让我们这样做”
So, Wikipedia would be spying on you. Wikipedia would calculate,
‎维基百科就会监视你 会计算
"What's the thing I can do to get this person to change a little bit
‎“我要做什么 才能代表一些商业利益
on behalf of some commercial interest? " Right?
‎让这个人产生一点改变？” 对吧？
And then it would change the entry.
‎然后就会改变整个词条
Can you imagine that?  Well, you should be able to,
‎你能想象吗？  ‎你应该能够想象得到
'cause that's exactly what's happening on Facebook.
‎因为在脸书页面上 就是这样的
It's exactly what's happening in your YouTube feed.
‎你的YouTube推送 就是这样的
When you go to Google and type in "Climate change is,"
‎当你登录谷歌 输入“气候变化是…”
you're going to see different results depending on where you live.
‎你会看到 根据你所居住的地区不同 ‎会出现不同的结果
‎（气候变化是）
In certain cities, you're gonna see it  autocomplete
‎在某些城市 你会看到自动完成…
with "climate change is a hoax."
‎“气候变化是一场骗局”
In other cases, you're gonna see
‎在其他地方 你将会看到
"climate change is causing the destruction of nature."
‎“气候变化是对自然的破坏”
And that's a function not of what the truth is about climate change,
‎这个功能 ‎提供的不都是气候变化的真相
but about where you happen to be Googling from
‎而是你在哪里进行谷歌搜索
and the particular things Google knows about your interests.
‎以及谷歌对你个人兴趣的了解
Even two friends who are so close to each other,
‎即便是两个非常亲近的朋友
who have almost the exact same set of friends,
‎他们两个有着完全相同的朋友圈子
they think, you know, "I'm going to news feeds on Facebook.
‎他们会认为 ‎“我们会看到脸书上的新推送
I'll see the exact same set of updates."
‎会看到完全相同的更新” ‎
But it's not like that at all.
但事实远非如此
They see completely different worlds
‎他们会看到完全不同的世界
because they're based on these computers calculating
‎因为这些是基于计算机的计算
what's perfect for each of them.
‎对每一个人来说 怎样最完美
‎（直播中）
The way to think about it is it's 2.7 billion Truman Shows.
‎想象这件事的一个方式是 ‎这是27亿人的《楚门的世界》
Each person has their own reality, with their own...
‎每一个人都有自己的现实 自己的…
facts.
‎事实
Why do you think that, uh, Truman has never come close
‎你觉得楚门为什么到现在都 ‎从来没有接近
to discovering the true nature of his world until now?
‎发现他所在世界的真实本质？
We accept the reality of the world with which we're presented.
‎我们接受了 ‎呈现在我们面前的世界就是现实
It's as simple as that.
‎就是这么简单
‎（直播中）
Over time, you have the false sense that everyone agrees with you,
‎随着时间推移 你会有一种错觉 ‎觉得每一个人都认同你
because everyone in your news feed sounds just like you.
‎因为给你推送的新闻中 ‎每个人都和你极其相似
And that once you're in that state, it turns out you're easily manipulated,
‎一旦你达到了这种状态 ‎你就很容易被操纵了
the same way you would be manipulated by a magician.
‎和你被魔术师操纵 是同样的方式
A magician shows you a card trick and says, "Pick a card, any card."
‎魔术师给你看纸牌魔术 跟你说 ‎“选一张牌 哪张都行”
What you don't realize was that they've done a set  up,
‎你没有意识到的是 ‎他们早就给你设好陷阱了
so you pick the card they want you to pick.
‎于是你选的那张牌 ‎是他们想让你选的
And that's how Facebook works. Facebook sits there and says,
‎这就是脸书的工作原理 ‎脸书坐在那里说
"Hey, you pick your friends. You pick the links that you follow."
‎“喂 选择你的朋友 ‎选择你关注的联系人”
But that's all nonsense. It's just like the magician.
‎根本是胡扯 它就跟魔术师一样
Facebook is in charge of your news feed.
‎脸书负责给你进行新闻推送
We all simply are operating on a different set of facts.
‎我们都不过是 ‎在基于不同的一系列事实行事
When that happens at scale,
‎当大范围发生时
you're no longer able to reckon with or even consume information
‎你就再也无法考虑甚至消化
that contradicts with that world view that you've created.
‎与你所创造的世界观相悖的信息了
That means we aren't actually being objective,
‎那就意味着 ‎我们其实不是客观、
constructive individuals.
有建设性的个体
Open up your eyes, don't believe the lies! Open up...
‎睁大你的眼睛 别相信谎言！睁大…
And then you look over at the other side,
‎然后你扫了一眼另一边
and you start to think, "How can those people be so stupid?
‎你开始想 ‎“这些人怎么会如此愚蠢？”
Look at all of this information that I'm constantly seeing.
‎他们也看到了我不停看到的这些信息
How are they not seeing that same information? "
‎他们怎么会看不到相同的信息？
And the answer is, "They're not seeing that same information."
‎问题的答案是 ‎“他们没有看到相同的信息”
Open up your eyes, don't believe the lies!
‎睁大你的眼睛 别相信谎言！
What are Republicans like?    People that don't have a clue.
‎共和党人什么样？  ‎愚昧无知
The Democrat Party is a crime syndicate, not a real political party.
‎民主党就是一个犯罪团伙 ‎不是真正的政治党派
A huge new Pew Research Center study of 10,000 American adults
‎皮尤研究中心一项全新的大型研究 ‎对一万名美国成年人进行调查
finds us more divided than ever,
‎发现我们比任何时候都要分裂
with  personal and political polarization at a 20  year high.
‎个人和政治两极分化达到20年来最高
You have more than a third of Republicans saying
‎有超过三分之一的共和党人说
the Democratic Party is a threat to the nation,
‎民主党是对这个国家的威胁
more than a quarter of Democrats saying the same thing about the Republicans.
‎民主党超过四分之一的人 ‎也这样说共和党
So many of the problems that we're discussing,
‎我们讨论的很多问题
like, around political polarization
‎比如政治两极分化
exist in spades on cable television.
‎在有线电视上大量存在
The media has this exact same problem,
‎媒体也有着同样的问题
where their business model, by and large,
‎整体上来说 他们的商业模式
is that they're selling our attention to advertisers.
‎是把我们的关注出售给广告商
And the Internet is just a new, even more efficient way to do that.
‎网络只是一个新的、更有效率的 ‎实现方式罢了
At YouTube, I was working on YouTube recommendations.
‎我曾在YouTube的工作 ‎是研究YouTube推荐
It worries me that an algorithm that I worked on
‎让我担心的是 我研究的一个算法
is actually increasing polarization in society.
‎增加了社会中的两极分化
But from the point of view of watch time,
‎但从观看时间来看
this polarization is extremely efficient at keeping people online.
‎这种两极分化 ‎在让人们持续在线观看上 极其有效
The only reason these teachers are teaching this stuff
‎这些老师教这些东西的唯一原因
is 'cause they're getting paid to.
‎是有人给他们钱 让他们教
It's absolutely absurd.      Hey, Benji.
‎  太扯了 ‎  喂 本杰
No soccer practice today?
‎今天没有足球训练吗？
Oh, there is. I'm just catching up on some news stuff.
‎有 我只想看看今天的新闻
Do research. Anything that sways from the Extreme Center
‎你去研究一下 极端中心说的任何话…
Wouldn't exactly call the stuff that you're watching news.
‎都不会把你看的这个东西称作新闻
You're always talking about how messed up everything is. So are they.
‎你总是说一切都那么混乱 确实是
But that stuff is just propaganda.
‎但那东西只是政治鼓吹
Neither is true. It's all about what makes sense.
‎没有一个是真的 ‎全都是让你觉得合理
Ben, I'm serious. That stuff is bad for you.
‎本 我很严肃 这些东西对你有害
You should go to soccer practice.      Mm.
‎你应该去足球训练
I share this stuff because I care.
‎我分享这个东西 是因为我在意
I care that you are being misled, and it's not okay. All right?
‎我在意你被误导 这是不对的 好吗？
People think the algorithm is designed
‎人们认为算法的设计
to give them what they really want, only it's not.
‎是给他们真正想要的 但其实不然
The algorithm is actually trying to find a few rabbit holes that are very powerful,
‎算法其实是在试图 ‎找到几个非常强大的兔子洞
trying to find which rabbit hole is the closest to your interest.
‎试图找到哪一个兔子洞 ‎最贴近你的兴趣
And then if you start watching one of those videos,
‎然后 如果你开始观看其中一个视频
then it will recommend it over and over again.
‎它就会不停继续推荐
It's not like anybody wants this to happen.
‎这种情况 并不是有人刻意为之
It's just that this is what the recommendation system is doing.
‎只是推荐系统一直在做而已
So much so that Kyrie Irving, the famous basketball player,
‎以至于著名篮球运动员凯里·欧文
uh, said he believed the Earth was flat, and he apologized later
‎说他相信地球是平的 后来又道歉
because he blamed it on a YouTube rabbit hole.
‎因为他把责任推给 ‎YouTube的一个兔子洞
You know, like, you click the YouTube click
‎你点击 YouTube视频
and it goes, like, how deep the rabbit hole goes.
‎它会继续 这个兔子洞能有多深
When he later came on to NPR to say,
‎他后来在国家公共广播电台上说
"I'm sorry for believing this. I didn't want to mislead people,"
‎“很抱歉我相信了这个 ‎我无意误导人们”
a bunch of students in a classroom were interviewed saying,
‎有人采访了教室中的一群学生 ‎他们说
"The round  Earthers got to him."
‎“相信地球是圆的人肯定找他谈了”
The flat  Earth conspiracy theory was recommended
‎地球平面阴谋论被算法
hundreds of millions of times by the algorithm.
‎推荐了几亿次
It's easy to think that it's just a few stupid people who get convinced,
‎很容易去想 ‎只有几个愚蠢的人被说服罢了
but the algorithm is getting smarter and smarter every day.
‎但是算法每一天都在变得更聪明
So, today, they are convincing the people that the Earth is flat,
‎今天 它们说服人们相信 地球是平的
but tomorrow, they will be convincing you of something that's false.
‎但是明天 它们就会说服你相信 ‎一个完全虚假的事情
On November 7th, the hashtag "Pizzagate" was born.
‎11月7日 话题标签‘披萨门’诞生了
Pizzagate...
‎披萨门…
Oh, boy.
‎天啊
I still am not 100 percent sure how this originally came about,
‎我还是不能百分之百确定 ‎这个最初是从哪里来的
but the idea that ordering a pizza meant ordering a trafficked person.
‎但是订披萨等于订一个贩卖的人口 ‎这个想法
As the groups got bigger on Facebook,
‎由于脸书上的多个小组越来越大
Facebook's recommendation engine started suggesting to regular users
‎脸书推荐引擎开始建议普通用户
that they join Pizzagate groups.
‎让他们加入披萨门小组
So, if a user was, for example, anti  vaccine or believed in chemtrails
‎所以 如果一个用户反对疫苗 ‎或者相信飞机喷洒重金属阴谋论
or had indicated to Facebook's algorithms in some way
‎或者对脸书的算法表示过
that they were prone to belief in conspiracy theories,
‎他们易于相信阴谋论
Facebook's recommendation engine would serve them  Pizzagate groups.
‎脸熟的推荐引擎 ‎就会推荐给他们披萨门小组
Eventually, this culminated in a man showing up with a gun,
‎最终 这件事达到高潮 ‎一名男子携枪出现
deciding that he was gonna go liberate the children from the basement
‎决定他要给披萨店地下室的 ‎那些孩子们自由
of the pizza place that did not have a basement.
‎而这个披萨店根本没有地下室
What were you doing?
‎  你当时在这个地方做什么？ ‎
Making sure there was nothing there.
确保这里什么都没有
Regarding?       Pedophile ring.
关于什么？ ‎  恋童癖怪圈
What?       Pedophile ring.
‎  什么？‎  恋童癖怪圈
He's talking about Pizzagate.
‎披萨门 他在说披萨门
This is an example of a conspiracy theory
‎这是阴谋论在所有社交媒体上
that was propagated across all social networks.
‎到处传播的一个例子
The social network's own recommendation engine
‎社交网络自己的推荐引擎
is voluntarily serving this up to people
‎自愿把这个东西推送给
who had never searched for the term "Pizzagate" in their life.
‎这辈子从来没有搜索过 ‎“披萨门”的人们
‎（披萨门 ‎民主党和恋童癖的深盘披萨）
There's a study, an MIT study,
‎有一个研究 麻省理工的研究
that fake news on Twitter spreads six times faster than true news.
‎说推特上传播的虚假新闻 ‎比真实新闻传播速度快六倍
What is that world gonna look like
‎当一个人有着高于另一个人
when one has a six  times advantage to the other one?
‎六倍的优势 这种世界会是什么样？
You can imagine these things are sort of like...
‎你可以想象 这些事情有点…
they... they tilt the floor of... of human behavior.
‎将人类行为的基础平面倾斜了
They make some behavior harder and some easier.
‎让一些行为更难 让一些行为更容易
And you're always free to walk up the hill,
‎你总是可以自由地走上山坡
but fewer people do,
‎但是这样做的人越来越少
and so, at scale, at society's scale, you really are just tilting the floor
‎所以大范围内 在整个社会范围内 ‎你就是将基础平面倾斜了
and changing what billions of people think and do.
‎改变了数十亿人的想法和行为
We've created a system that biases towards false information.
‎我们创造了一个 ‎偏心于虚假消息的体系
Not because we want to,
‎并不是因为我们想这样做
but because false information makes the companies more money
‎而是因为虚假信息比真实信息 ‎能让各个公司
than the truth. The truth is boring.
‎赚到更多钱 真实信息比较无聊
It's a disinformation  for  profit business model.
‎这是一个 ‎利用虚假信息牟利的商业模式
You make money the more you allow unregulated messages
‎允许未受监管的信息传送给更多的人
to reach anyone for the best price.
‎卖出最好的价钱 以此来赚钱
Because climate change?  Yeah.
‎因为气候变化？对
It's a hoax. Yeah, it's real. That's the point.
‎这是骗局 对 是真的 这才是重点
The more they talk about it and the more they divide us,
‎他们谈论这件事情越多 ‎就越会将我们分化
the more they have the power, the more...
‎他们越有力量 就越有控制权
Facebook has trillions of these news feed posts.
‎脸书有万亿个新闻推送贴
They can't know what's real or what's true...
‎他们无法知道哪些是真的 ‎哪些是事实…
which is why this conversation is so critical right now.
‎所以当下这个议题 才如此重要
It's not just COVID  19 that's spreading fast.
‎传播迅速的 不只是新冠病毒
There's a flow of misinformation online about the virus.
‎网上有关于这个病毒的大量虚假信息
The notion drinking water
‎多喝水能将新冠病毒
will flush coronavirus from your system
‎从你身体中冲走的提议
is one of several myths about the virus circulating on social media.
‎是在社交媒体上广泛流传的 ‎该病毒的谜题之一
The government planned this event, created the virus,
‎这是政府计划的事件 ‎创造了这个病毒
and had a simulation of how the countries would react.
‎来模拟世界各国将会如何应对
Coronavirus is a... a hoax.
‎新冠病毒是一场骗局
SARS, coronavirus.
‎非典 新冠病毒
And look at when it was made. 2018.
‎看看这是什么时候制造的 2018年
I think the US government started this shit.
‎我觉得是美国政府开始的这场闹剧
Nobody is sick. Nobody is sick. Nobody knows anybody who's sick.
‎根本没有人生病 没人生病
‎没有人认识哪个人真正生病了
Maybe the government is using the coronavirus as an excuse
‎或许是政府在利用新冠病毒当借口
to get everyone to stay inside because something else is happening.
‎让所有人留在家 ‎因为有其他的事情要发生
Coronavirus is not killing people,
‎新冠病毒不会杀人
it's the 5G radiation that they're pumping out.
‎他们是在掩盖5G辐射害死的人
‎（5G信号塔被割倒焚烧）
We're being bombarded with rumors.
‎我们被谣言轰炸
People are blowing up actual physical cell phone towers.
‎人们去毁掉了真实的手机信号塔
We see Russia and China spreading rumors and conspiracy theories.
‎我们看到俄罗斯和中国 ‎传播谣言和阴谋论
This morning, panic and protest in Ukraine as...
‎今天早上 乌克兰的恐慌与抗议…
People have no idea what's true, and now it's a matter of life and death.
‎人们不知道什么是真相 ‎现在已经闹出人命了
Those sources that are spreading coronavirus misinformation
‎那些传播新冠病毒虚假信息的来源
have amassed something like 52 million engagements.
‎积累了5200万人参与
You're saying that silver solution would be effective.
‎你是说 胶银溶液会有效
Well, let's say it hasn't been tested on this strain of the coronavirus, but...
‎我们这样说吧 ‎虽然没有用新冠病毒的毒株测试过
What we're seeing with COVID is just an extreme version
‎我们看到的新冠病毒 ‎只是发生在我们信息生态系统中的
of what's happening across our information ecosystem.
‎一个极端案例
‎（惠特默 希特勒）
Social media amplifies exponential gossip and exponential hearsay
‎社交媒体放大了增长迅速的谣言 ‎和增长迅速的道听途说
to the point that we don't know what's true,
‎以至于我们都不知道 什么是真了
no matter what issue we care about.
‎不管我们关注的是什么问题
He discovers this.
他发现了这个
Ben.
本
Are you still on the team?       Mm  hmm.
‎你还在队里吗？
Okay, well, I'm gonna get a snack before practice
‎好 如果你想来 我在训练之前 ‎先去吃点零食 你要来吗？
if you... wanna come.
先去吃点零食 你要来吗？
Hm?
嗯？
You know, never mind.
‎当我没说
Nine out of ten people are dissatisfied right now.
‎当前 十个人当中 有九个人不满意
The EC is like any political movement in history, when you think about it.
‎你仔细想想 极端中心和历史上 ‎任何政治运动无异
We are standing up, and we are... we are standing up to this noise.
‎我们要站起来反抗 ‎我们要站起来反抗这种杂音
You are my people. I trust you guys.
‎你是我的人民 我相信你们
The Extreme Center content is brilliant.   He absolutely loves it.
‎  极端中心的内容好棒 ‎  他非常喜欢
Running an auction.
‎运行一个拍卖
840 bidders. He sold for 4.35 cents to a weapons manufacturer.
‎843个竞标人 他以4.35美分 ‎卖给了一个武器生产商
Let's promote some of these events.
‎我们来宣传一下这些活动
Upcoming rallies in his geographic zone later this week.
‎这星期晚些时候 ‎将在这片地理区域发生的群众集会
I've got a new vlogger lined up, too.
‎新的视频博主也安排好了
And... and, honestly, I'm telling you, I'm willing to do whatever it takes.
‎说实话 我告诉你 ‎我愿意付出任何代价
And I mean whatever.
‎我说 任何代价
Subscribe...      Ben?
‎  订阅… ‎  本？
...and also come back because I'm telling you, yo...
‎…记得回来 因为我告诉你们…
...I got some real big things comin'.
‎我后面会有大事件
Some real big things.
‎非常大的事件
One of the problems with Facebook is that, as a tool of persuasion,
‎脸书的一个问题是 ‎作为一个有劝说性质的工具
it may be the greatest thing ever created.
‎它或许是史上最伟大的发明
Now, imagine what that means in the hands of a dictator or an authoritarian.
‎现在 你来想象一下 落在独裁者 ‎或者集权主义者手中 会怎样
If you want to control the population of your country,
‎如果你想控制你们国家的人民
there has never been a tool as effective as Facebook.
‎从未有过像脸书这样有效的工具
Some of the most troubling implications
‎一个问题最大的影响是
of governments and other bad actors weaponizing social media,
‎一些政府和其他不良人士 ‎把社交媒体当作武器
um, is that it has led to real, offline harm.
‎导致了真实的线下伤害
I think the most prominent example
‎我认为最明显的案例
that's gotten a lot of press is what's happened in Myanmar.
‎广泛被媒体关注的 ‎是缅甸发生的事情
‎（缅甸总统办公室）
In Myanmar, when people think of the Internet,
‎在缅甸 人们想到网络时
what they are thinking about is Facebook.
‎他们想到的 是脸书
And what often happens is when people buy their cell phone,
‎经常发生的事情是 人们买了手机
the cell phone shop owner will actually preload Facebook on there for them
‎手机店主会提前帮他们下载好脸书
and open an account for them.
‎帮他们开好账户
And so when people get their phone, the first thing they open
‎于是人们拿到手机之后 ‎第一个打开的应用
and the only thing they know how to open is Facebook.
‎他们唯一知道怎样打开的 就是脸书
Well, a new bombshell investigation exposes Facebook's growing struggle
‎一个新的震惊调查显示 ‎脸书日益增长的
to tackle hate speech in Myanmar.
‎对抗缅甸仇恨言论的难题
‎（停止杀害穆斯林）
Facebook really gave the military and other bad actors
‎脸书真的给军人和其他不良人士
a new way to manipulate public opinion
‎一种控制公众言论的新手段
and to help incite violence against the Rohingya Muslims
‎并协助煽动 ‎针对罗兴亚族穆斯林的暴力
that included mass killings,
‎包括大屠杀
burning of entire villages,
‎焚烧整个村庄
mass rape, and other serious crimes against humanity
‎违反人道主义的 ‎大规模强奸和其他严重犯罪行为
that have now led
‎已经导致
to 700,000  Rohingya Muslims having to flee the country.
七十万罗兴亚族穆斯林 ‎逃出这个国家
It's not that highly motivated propagandists
‎这种情绪高涨的鼓吹 ‎
haven't existed before.
以前并不是没有出现过
It's that the platforms make it possible
‎只是这个平台实现了
to spread manipulative narratives with phenomenal ease,
‎让操纵性言论传播变得异常容易
and without very much money.
‎也不用花多少钱
If I want to manipulate an election,
‎如果我想操纵竞选
I can now go into a conspiracy theory group on Facebook,
‎我现在可以去脸书上的 ‎一个阴谋论小组
and I can find 100 people
‎可以找到一百个人
who believe that the Earth is completely flat
‎他们深信地球是平的
and think it's all this conspiracy theory that we landed on the moon,
‎认为我们登月 完全是阴谋论
and I can tell Facebook, "Give me 1,000 users who look like that."
‎我可以告诉脸书 ‎“给我推荐一千个这种用户”
Facebook will happily send me thousands of users that look like them
‎脸书会非常开心地发给我 ‎几千个这种用户
that I can now hit with more conspiracy theories.
‎我现在可以给他们讲更多的阴谋论
Sold for 3.4 cents an impression.
‎以3.4美分卖了一个印象
New EC video to promote.   Another ad teed up.
‎推广新的极端中心  ‎再安排一个广告
Algorithms and manipulative politicians
‎算法和操纵人的政治家
are becoming so expert
‎在学习如何激发我们的方面
at learning how to trigger us,
‎变得非常专业
getting so good at creating fake news that we absorb as if it were reality,
‎非常擅长制造我们容易接受的 ‎虚假新闻 假装这就是事实
and confusing us into believing those lies.
‎给我们造成混乱 ‎让我们相信这些谎言
It's as though we have less and less control
‎我们似乎对自己是怎样的人 ‎
over who we are and what we believe.
自己的信仰 有越来越少的控制权
...so they can pick sides.
‎…来让他们选择站队
There's lies here, and there's lies over there.
‎到处都是谎言
So they can keep the power,
‎这样他们就能保持住权力
so they can control everything.
‎这样他们就能控制一切
They can control our minds,
‎他们可以控制我们的思想 ‎
so that they can keep their secrets.
这样他们就可以保守他们的秘密
‎（质疑真相）
‎（疾控中心承认掩盖疫苗/自闭症）
Imagine a world where no one believes anything true.
‎想象一个没有人相信任何真相的世界
‎（疫苗不普适所有人 ‎我们的基因就是证据）
Everyone believes the government's lying to them.
‎所有人都相信 政府在骗他们
Everything is a conspiracy theory.
‎一切都是阴谋论
"I shouldn't trust anyone. I hate the other side."
‎“我不应该相信任何人 ‎我痛恨对立面”
That's where all this is heading.
‎一切正在向这个方向发展
The political earthquakes in Europe continue to rumble.
‎欧洲的政治地震 余震不止
This time, in Italy and Spain.
‎这一次 轮到了意大利和西班牙
Overall, Europe's traditional, centrist coalition lost its majority
‎整体上来说 欧洲传统的 ‎中间派联合政府失去了大多数人支持
while far right and far left populist parties made gains.
‎同时极左和极右民粹主义政党 ‎获得更多支持
‎（中心）
Back up.
‎退后
Okay, let's go.
‎好  我们走
These accounts were deliberately, specifically attempting
‎这些账户专门故意试图
to sow political discord in Hong Kong.
‎散播香港政治纷争信息
All right, Ben.
‎好 本
What does it look like to be a country
‎生活在一个全部信息来自于脸书
that's entire diet is Facebook and social media?
‎和社交媒体的国家 是什么感觉？
Democracy crumbled quickly.
‎民主迅速崩溃
Six months.
‎六个月
After that chaos in Chicago,
‎芝加哥的混乱发生后
violent clashes between protesters and supporters...
‎抗议者和支持者之间的暴力冲突…
Democracy is facing a crisis of confidence.
‎民主正面临着信心危机
What we're seeing is a global assault on democracy.
‎我们看到的 是对全球民主的攻击
‎（极端中心）
Most of the countries that are targeted are countries
‎多数目标国家 都是
that run democratic elections.
‎进行民主选举的国家
This is happening at scale.
‎大范围发生
By state actors, by people with millions of dollars saying,
‎国家行动者、家财万贯的富翁说
"I wanna destabilize Kenya. I wanna destabilize Cameroon.
‎“我想让肯尼亚动摇 ‎我想让喀麦隆动摇
Oh, Angola?  That only costs this much."
‎安哥拉？只要这么一点钱”
An extraordinary election took place Sunday in Brazil.
‎巴西上周日举行了一场特别的选举
With a campaign that's been powered by social media.
‎选举动员是社交媒体驱动的
We in the tech industry have created the tools
‎我们技术产业的人创造了
to destabilize and erode the fabric of society
‎动摇和侵蚀社会结构的工具
in every country,  all at once, everywhere.
‎所有国家都在同时发生 ‎世界各地都在发生
You have this in Germany, Spain, France, Brazil, Australia.
‎德国、西班牙、法国 ‎巴西、澳大利亚都有发生
Some of the most "developed nations" in the world
‎一些世界上最发达的国家
are now imploding on each other,
‎正在互相爆破
and what do they have in common?
‎他们有什么共同点？
Knowing what you know now,
‎基于你当前的了解
do you believe Facebook impacted the results of the 2016 election?
‎你相信脸书 ‎影响了2016年大选的结果吗？
Oh, that's... that is hard.
‎这个问题好难回答
You know,  it's... the...
‎你知道 这个…
the reality is, well, there were so many different forces at play.
‎事实是 ‎有很多不同的力量在产生影响
Representatives from Facebook, Twitter, and Google are back on Capitol Hill
‎脸书、推特和谷歌的代表们 ‎回到国会山
for a second day of testimony
‎对俄罗斯干预2016年大选问题
about Russia's interference in the 2016 election.
‎进行第二天的证词发言
The manipulation by third parties is not a hack.
‎第三方政党的操纵没有黑入
Right?  The Russians didn't hack Facebook.
‎对吧？俄罗斯没有黑入脸书
What they did was they used the tools that Facebook created
‎他们所做的是 利用脸书 ‎
for legitimate advertisers and legitimate users,
为合法广告商与合法用户创造的工具
and they applied it to a nefarious purpose.
‎用到了罪恶的用途中
It's like remote  control warfare.
‎就像是远程控制的战争
One country can manipulate another one
‎一个国家可以操纵另一个国家
without actually invading its physical borders.
‎都不用真正入侵实体边境
We're seeing violent images. It appears to be a dumpster
‎我们看到这些暴力的画面
being pushed around...
‎这是一个被推来推去的垃圾箱…
But it wasn't about who you wanted to vote for.
‎但问题不是你想投票给谁
It was about sowing total chaos and division in society.
‎问题是在社会中散播混乱和分歧
Now, this was in Huntington Beach. A march...
‎这是在霍廷顿海滩市的示威…
It's about making two sides
‎问题是制造了两个对立面
who couldn't hear each other anymore,
‎丝毫不再听取对方的观点
who didn't want to hear each other anymore,
‎不再想听对方的观点
who didn't trust each other anymore.
‎不再相信对方
This is a city where hatred was laid bare
‎这是仇恨被暴露出
and transformed into racial violence.
‎并转化成种族暴力的城市
‎（弗吉尼亚紧张局势 ‎暴力当天致三人遇害）
Ben!
‎本！
Cassandra!
‎卡桑德拉！
Cass!   Ben!
‎  卡桑！ ‎  本！
Come here! Come here!
‎过来！
Arms up. Arms up. Get down on your knees. Now, down.
‎举起手 膝盖跪地 快 跪下
Calm       Ben!
‎  冷静…… ‎  本！
Hey! Hands up!
‎喂！手举起来！
Turn around. On the ground.  On the ground!
‎转过去 趴地上
Do we want this system for sale to the highest bidder?
‎我们希望这个系统 ‎售卖出最高的竞价吗？
For democracy to be completely for sale, where you can reach any mind you want,
‎完全出售民主 ‎你可以控制任何你想控制的思想
target a lie to that specific population, and create culture wars?
‎对特定人群设定谎言 ‎制造文化战争？
Do we want that?
‎我们希望这样吗？
We are a nation of people...
‎我们这个国家的人民…
that no longer speak to each other.
‎不再和彼此说话了
We are a nation of people who have stopped being friends with people
‎我们这个国家的人民 ‎不再和彼此交友了
because of who they voted for in the last election.
‎只因为他们在上一次竞选中投票的人
We are a nation of people who have isolated ourselves
‎我们这个国家的人民孤立了自己
to only watch channels that tell us that we're right.
‎只看认同我们的那些频道
My message here today is that tribalism is ruining us.
‎我今天想传达的信息是 ‎部落主义正在毁掉我们
It is tearing our country apart.
‎它正在撕裂我们这个国家
It is no way for sane adults to act.
‎正常的成年人 不可能这样做
If everyone's entitled to their own facts,
‎如果每个人都有权执着于自己的真相
there's really no need for compromise, no need for people to come together.
‎就真没有必要妥协 ‎没有必要让人们团结了
In fact, there's really no need for people to interact.
‎事实上 真的没有必要让人们互动
We need to have...
‎我们需要
some shared understanding of reality. Otherwise, we aren't a country.
‎对现实有一些共同的理解  不然 我们就不是一个国家了
So, uh, long  term, the solution here is to build more AI tools
‎（扎克伯格先生）
‎所以长期来看 解决办法 ‎是建造更多的人工智能工具
that find patterns of people using the services that no real person would do.
‎找到人们使用这些服务的行为模式 ‎这是任何一个真人都做不到的
We are allowing the technologists to frame this as a problem
‎我们允许技术专家 把这个当做一个
that they're equipped to solve.
‎他们有能力解决的问题呈现
That is... That's a lie.
‎这是骗人的
People talk about AI as if it will know truth.
‎人们谈论人工智能 ‎好像人工智能知道真理一样
AI's not gonna solve these problems.
‎人工智能无法解决这些问题
AI cannot solve the problem of fake news.
‎人工智能无法解决虚假新闻的问题
Google doesn't have the option of saying,
‎谷歌没有选择去说
"Oh, is this conspiracy?  Is this truth? " Because they don't know what truth is.
‎“这是阴谋论？这是真相吗？”
‎因为它们不知道 真相是什么
They don't have a...
‎它们没有
They don't have a proxy for truth that's better than a click.
真相的代理服务器 ‎只有点击
If we don't agree on what is true
‎如果我们不同意真相
or that there is such a thing as truth,
‎或者不同意存在真相
we're toast.
‎我们就完蛋了
This is the problem beneath other problems
‎这是其他问题之下的问题
because if we can't agree on what's true,
‎因为如果我们不能认同真相
then we can't navigate out of any of our problems.
‎那我们就无法找到 ‎我们任何一个问题的解决方法
We should suggest Flat Earth Football Club.
‎我们应该建议他 ‎关注平面地球足球俱乐部
Don't show him sports updates. He doesn't engage.
‎别再给他展示运动消息了 ‎他不感兴趣
A lot of people in Silicon Valley subscribe to some kind of theory
‎硅谷的很多人相信一种理论
that we're building some global super brain,
‎我们正在建造一些全球的超级大脑
and all of our users are just interchangeable little neurons,
‎我们所有的用户 ‎都只是可交互的神经元
no one of which is important.
‎他们一点都不重要
And it subjugates people into this weird role
‎它让人们服从于这样一个奇怪的角色
where you're just, like, this little computing element
‎你就像是一个小的编程元素
that we're programming through our behavior manipulation
‎我们通过我们的行为操纵去 编程
for the service of this giant brain, and you don't matter.
‎为了服务于这个巨型大脑 ‎你根本不重要
You're not gonna get paid. You're not gonna get acknowledged.
‎不会给你钱 不会告诉你真相
You don't have self  determination.
‎你没有自主权
We'll sneakily just manipulate you because you're a computing node,
‎我们会鬼祟地操纵你 ‎因为你是编程中的结点
so we need to program you  'cause that's what you do with computing nodes.
‎所以我们需要将你编程 ‎因为我们就要这样对待编程中的结点
Oh, man.
‎天啊
When you think about technology and it being an existential threat,
‎当你想到技术 ‎技术是一种人类存亡的威胁
you know, that's a big claim, and...
‎这个指控很严重…
it's easy to then, in your mind, think, "Okay, so, there I am with the phone...
‎然后你的脑中就会很容易想 ‎“好 我正在拿着手机
scrolling, clicking, using it.
‎互动、点击、使用
Like, where's the existential threat?
‎人类存亡的威胁在哪里？
Okay, there's the supercomputer.
‎好 有一个超级电脑
The other side of the screen, pointed at my brain,
‎在屏幕的另一端 正指向我的大脑
got me to watch one more video. Where's the existential threat? "
‎让我再看一个视频 ‎人类存亡的威胁在哪里？”
It's not about the technology being the existential threat.
‎技术并不是人类存亡的威胁
‎（劝服性技术 美国参议院听政会）
It's the technology's ability
‎是技术能够把
to bring out the worst in society...
‎社会中最坏的东西带出来的能力
...and the worst in society being the existential threat.
‎社会中最坏的东西 ‎才是人类存亡的威胁
‎（美国参议院）
If technology creates...
‎如果技术创造了
mass chaos,
公众混乱
outrage, incivility,
‎愤怒、无礼
lack of trust in each other,
‎彼此缺乏信任
loneliness, alienation, more polarization,
‎孤独、疏远、更加两极分化
more election hacking, more populism,
‎更多大选黑入、更多平民政治
more distraction and inability to focus on the real issues...
‎让人更加分散注意力 ‎无法集中在真正的问题上…
that's just society.
‎那只是社会
And now society is incapable of healing itself
‎现在社会无法自愈
and just devolving into a kind of chaos.
‎转移成了一种混乱的形式
This affects everyone, even if you don't use these products.
‎这影响着每一个人 ‎即使你不使用这些产品
These things have become digital Frankensteins
‎这些事情变成了数码的科学怪人
that are  terraforming the world in their image,
‎让这个世界变成他们现象中的样子
whether it's the mental health of children
‎不论是儿童的心理健康
or our politics and our political discourse,
‎还是我们的政治 我们的政治演说
without taking responsibility for taking over the public square.
‎而不用因为控制公众舆论 ‎承担责任
So, again, it comes back to       And who do you think's responsible?
‎  所以 还是要回到… ‎  你觉得这一切怪谁？
I think we have to have the platforms be responsible
‎我认为我们必须让平台负起责任
for when they take over election advertising,
‎因为他们接管大选广告的时候
they're responsible for protecting elections.
‎就要负责保护大选
When they take over mental health of kids or Saturday morning,
‎当他们接管儿童心理健康 ‎或是儿童频道的时候
they're responsible for protecting Saturday morning.
‎他们就有责任保护好儿童频道
The race to keep people's attention isn't going away.
‎保持人们关注的竞争不会结束
Our technology's gonna become more integrated into our lives, not less.
‎我们的技术会在我们生活中更加集成 ‎而不会减少
The AIs are gonna get better at predicting what keeps us on the screen,
‎人工智能会更加擅长预判 ‎什么内容能让我们持续盯着屏幕
not worse at predicting what keeps us on the screen.
‎而不是做出更差的预判
I... I am 62 years old,
‎我已经62岁了
getting older every minute, the more this conversation goes on...
‎随着这个对话继续进行 ‎我每一分钟都在变老
...but... but I will tell you that, um...
‎但我会告诉你
I'm probably gonna be dead and gone, and I'll probably be thankful for it,
‎到时候我可能已经死了 不在了 ‎但我可能会为此感恩
when all this shit comes to fruition.
‎因为当这些恐怖的东西结出恶果
Because... Because I think that this scares me to death.
‎我觉得能吓死我
Do... Do you... Do you see it the same way?
‎你也这样看吗？
Or am I overreacting to a situation that I don't know enough about?
‎还是我对一个我不够了解的情况 ‎过度反应了？
What are you most worried about?
‎你最担心什么？
I think, in the... in the shortest time horizon...
‎我认为在最短的时间范围内…
civil war.
‎是内战
If we go down the current status quo for, let's say, another 20 years...
‎如果现在的常态继续下去 ‎我们说再过20年
we probably destroy our civilization through willful ignorance.
‎我们很可能会因为故意无知 ‎毁掉我们的文明
We probably fail to meet the challenge of climate change.
‎我们或许会无法应对气候变化的挑战
We probably degrade the world's democracies
‎我们或许会瓦解世界的民主
so that they fall into some sort of bizarre autocratic dysfunction.
‎最终衰落成一种奇怪的独裁机能障碍
We probably ruin the global economy.
‎我们或许会毁掉全球经济
Uh, we probably, um, don't survive.
‎我们或许会无法存活
You know, I... I really do view it as existential.
‎我真的把它看做 ‎人类生死存亡的大问题
Is this the last generation of people
‎这会是知道在这种幻象发生之前
that are gonna know what it was like before this illusion took place?
‎世界是什么样的最后一代人吗？
Like, how do you wake up from the matrix when you don't know you're in the matrix?
‎如果你不知道自己在矩阵中 ‎你要怎么从矩阵中醒来？
‎（“不论是乌托邦还是毁灭 ‎都是一场一触即发的接力赛…）
‎（直接通往最后一刻…” ‎——巴克敏斯特·富勒）
A lot of what we're saying sounds like it's just this...
‎你知道 我们说的很多话 ‎听起来像是…
one  sided doom and gloom.
‎片面的悲观
Like, "Oh, my God, technology's just ruining the world
‎“天啊 技术正在毁灭世界
and it's ruining kids,"
‎正在毁灭孩子们”
and it's like... "No."
‎不是这样的
It's confusing because it's simultaneous utopia...and dystopia.
‎这很困惑 ‎因为这同时是乌托邦和毁灭
Like, I could hit a button on my phone, and a car shows up in 30 seconds,
‎我可以在手机按一个按钮 ‎30秒后就能出现一辆车
and I can go exactly where I need to go.
‎我就可以去想去的任何地方
That is magic. That's amazing.
‎这简直是魔法 太神奇了
When we were making the like button,
‎我们制作“点赞”按钮的时候
our entire motivation was, "Can we spread positivity and love in the world? "
‎我们全部的动机是 “我们可以 ‎在世界中传播积极和爱吗？”
The idea that, fast  forward to today, and teens would be getting depressed
‎时间快进到当下 ‎青少年会因为没有得到足够多的点赞
when they don't have enough likes,
‎而抑郁 这个想法
or it could be leading to political polarization
‎或者会导致政治两极分化
was nowhere on our radar.
‎当时是完全无法想象的
I don't think these guys set out to be evil.
‎我不认为这些人 ‎最开始的目标是邪恶的
It's just the business model that has a problem.
‎只是这个商业模式有问题
You could shut down the service and destroy whatever it is
‎你可以关掉服务 毁掉不管这是什么
$20 billion of shareholder value     and get sued and...
‎200亿美元的股东利益 被起诉…
But you can't, in practice, put the genie back in the bottle.
‎但现实是 覆水难收
You can make some tweaks, but at the end of the day,
‎你可以做出一些小的调整 但是最终
you've gotta grow revenue and usage, quarter over quarter. It's...
‎你要增加收益和使用 ‎每一个季度都要增加
The bigger it gets, the harder it is for anyone to change.
‎规模做得越大 越难让任何人改变
What I see is a bunch of people who are trapped by a business model,
‎我看到的是一群被困住的人 ‎被商业模式
an economic incentive, and shareholder pressure
‎经济奖励和股东压力困住
that makes it almost impossible to do something else.
‎几乎无法做其他的任何事情
I think we need to accept that it's okay
‎我认为我们应该接受
for companies to be focused on making money.
‎公司专注于挣钱 是合情合理的
What's not okay is when there's no regulation, no rules,
‎不合情合理的是 ‎当没有监管、没有规定、
and no competition,
没有竞争
and the companies are acting as sort of  de facto governments.
‎公司在充当实际政府部门
And then they're saying, "Well, we can regulate ourselves."
‎然后他们说“我们可以监管自己”
I mean, that's just a lie. That's just ridiculous.
‎这肯定是骗人的 怎么可能呢
Financial incentives kind of run the world,
‎经济奖励可以说运营着世界
so any solution to this problem
‎所以这个问题的任何解决方案
has to realign the financial incentives.
‎一定要符合经济奖励
There's no fiscal reason for these companies to change.
‎这些公司没有需要改变的财政理由
And that is why I think we need regulation.
‎所以我才认为 我们需要监管
The phone company has tons of sensitive data about you,
‎手机公司有无数的关于你的敏感数据
and we have a lot of laws that make sure they don't do the wrong things.
‎我们有很多法律去保证 ‎他们不会利用这些数据做错事
We have almost no laws around digital privacy, for example.
‎在数码隐私上 我们几乎没有立法
We could tax data collection and processing
‎我们可以对数据收集和处理收税
the same way that you, for example, pay your water bill
‎原理等同于你交水费
by monitoring the amount of water that you use.
‎监控你自己的用水量
You tax these companies on the data assets that they have.
‎让这些公司因为持有的数据资产交税
It gives them a fiscal reason
‎就能给他们一个财政理由
to not acquire every piece of data on the planet.
‎不去获取地球上每一条数据
The law runs way behind on these things,
‎立法在这方面太落后了
but what I know is the current situation exists not for the protection of users,
‎但据我所知 当前状况的存在 ‎不是为了保护用户
but for the protection of the rights and privileges
‎而是为了保护这些巨型的
of these gigantic, incredibly wealthy companies.
‎超级富有公司的权利和特权
Are we always gonna defer to the richest, most powerful people?
‎我们要一直听从最有钱 ‎最有权力的人吗？
Or are we ever gonna say,
‎还是我们要说
"You know, there are times when there is a national interest.
‎“有时候 确实是有国家利益
There are times when the interests of people, of users,
‎有时候 人民的利益 用户利益
is actually more important
‎其实比一个
than the profits of somebody who's already a billionaire"?
‎已经是亿万富翁的人的利益 ‎更加重要？”
These markets undermine democracy, and they undermine freedom,
‎这些市场削弱了民主 削弱了自由
and they should be outlawed.
‎应该对他们进行法律的制裁
This is not a radical proposal.
‎这不是激进的提议
There are other markets that we outlaw.
‎我们有法律制裁的其他市场
We outlaw markets in human organs.
‎我们制裁人类器官贩卖市场
We outlaw markets in human slaves.
‎我们制裁人类奴隶市场
Because they have inevitable destructive consequences.
‎因为它们都有不可避免的破坏性后果
We live in a world
‎我们生活的世界
in which a tree is worth more, financially, dead than alive,
‎死去的树比活着的树更有经济价值
in a world in which a whale is worth more dead than alive.
‎这个世界 死去的鲸 ‎比活着的鲸更有价值
For so long as our economy works in that way
‎只要我们的经济这样运转
and corporations go unregulated,
‎公司不受监管
they're going to continue to destroy trees,
‎它们就会继续破坏树木
to kill whales,
‎继续捕杀鲸
to mine the earth, and to continue to pull oil out of the ground,
‎在地球上挖矿 从地下抽石油
even though we know it is destroying the planet
‎虽然我们知道 这样做会破坏地球
and we know that it's going to leave a worse world for future generations.
‎我们知道 这样做会为未来几代人 ‎留下一个更不堪的世界
This is short  term thinking
‎这是目光短浅
based on this religion of profit at all costs,
‎为了利益牺牲一切的信仰
as if somehow, magically, each corporation acting in its selfish interest
‎指望每个 ‎只顾自己私利的公司会突然神奇地
is going to produce the best result.
‎去产生最好的结果
This has been affecting the environment for a long time.
‎这已经影响环境很久了
What's frightening, and what hopefully is the last straw
‎恐怖的是 希望这是 ‎压倒骆驼的最后一根稻草
that will make us wake up as a civilization
‎让我们作为文明的种族 去幡然醒悟
to how flawed this theory has been in the first place
‎这个理论最初就有很多缺点
is to see that now we're the tree, we're the whale.
‎让我们看到 我们现在就是树 就是鲸
Our attention can be mined.
‎我们的关注就是被挖掘的矿产
We are more profitable to a corporation
‎如果我们花时间盯着一个屏幕
if we're spending time staring at a screen,
‎盯着一个广告 对公司而言
staring at an ad,
‎比我们用这个时间
than if we're spending that time living our life in a rich way.
‎过自己丰富的生活 更加有利可图
And so, we're seeing the results of that.
‎我们看到了这样的后果
We're seeing corporations using powerful artificial intelligence
‎我们看到公司利用强大的人工智能
to outsmart us and figure out how to pull our attention
‎凌驾在我们的智能之上 ‎研究怎样拉拢我们的关注
toward the things they want us to look at,
‎让我们去看 他们想让我们看的东西
rather than the things that are most consistent
‎而不是让我们看 ‎与我们目标、价值观
with our goals and our values and our lives.
‎与我们的生活最为一致的东西
‎（史蒂夫·乔布斯 今日演讲者）
What a computer is,
‎电脑对我来说 是…
is it's the most remarkable tool that we've ever come up with.
‎是我们人类历史上 最神奇的发明
And it's the equivalent of a bicycle for our minds.
‎相当于是我们思想的自行车
The idea of humane technology, that's where Silicon Valley got its start.
‎人道技术的创想 是硅谷最初的目标
And we've lost sight of it because it became the cool thing to do,
‎我们已经背离了这个目标 ‎因为这样做比较酷
as opposed to the right thing to do.
‎而不是这样做比较正确
The Internet was, like, a weird, wacky place.
‎网络就是一个奇怪的、可笑的地方
It was experimental.
‎它是实验性的
Creative things happened on the Internet, and certainly, they do still,
‎网络上发生着有创意的事情 ‎当然现在也有发生
but, like, it just feels like this, like, giant mall.
‎但是感觉像一个巨大的商场
You know, it's just like, "God, there's gotta be...
‎就是“天啊 ‎
there's gotta be more to it than that."
肯定不止表面上这么简单”
I guess I'm just an optimist.
‎我想我只是一个乐观主义者
'Cause I think we can change what social media looks like and means.
‎因为我认为 ‎我们可以改变社交媒体的样子和方式
The way the technology works is not a law of physics.
‎技术的工作方式不是物理学定律 ‎
It is not set in stone.
它不是一成不变的
These are choices that human beings like myself have been making.
‎这些都是像我这样的人类 ‎做出的选择
And human beings can change those technologies.
‎人类可以改变这些技术
And the question now is whether or not we're willing to admit
‎现在的问题是 我们是否愿意承认
that those bad outcomes are coming directly as a product of our work.
‎这些后果 是我们杰作的直接产物
It's that we built these things, and we have a responsibility to change it.
‎这些东西是我们建立起来的 ‎我们有责任去改变它们
The attention extraction model
‎提取关注模型 ‎
is not how we want to treat human beings.
不是我们想对待人类的方式
Is it just me or...
‎只有我这样想吗？还是…
Poor sucker.
‎可悲的人
The fabric of a healthy society
‎一个健康社会的结构
depends on us getting off this corrosive business model.
‎要依靠我们脱离这种 ‎有破坏性的商业模型
We can demand that these products be designed humanely.
‎我们可以要求 ‎这些产品进行人道设计
We can demand to not be treated as an extractable resource.
‎我们可以要求 ‎不被当做可以提取的资源对待
The intention could be: "How do we make the world better? "
‎我们的动机可以是 ‎“我们怎样让这个世界变得更好？”
Throughout history,
‎在整个人类历史中
every single time something's gotten better,
‎每一次有事物变得更好
it's because somebody has come along to say,
‎都是因为有人站出来说
"This is stupid. We can do better."
‎“这太蠢了 我们可以做得更好”
Like, it's the critics that drive improvement.
‎是批判者驱动着改进
It's the critics who are the true optimists.
‎批判者才是真正的乐观主义者
Hello.
‎你好
I mean, it seems kind of crazy, right?
‎感觉有点疯狂 是吧？
It's like the fundamental way that this stuff is designed...
‎这东西的设计基本方式
isn't going in a good direction.
‎就不会朝着好的方向发展
Like, the entire thing.
‎整个社交媒体
So, it sounds crazy to say we need to change all that,
‎我说要改变这一切 ‎听起来有点疯狂
but that's what we need to do.
‎但我们需要这样做
Think we're gonna get there?
‎你觉得这一天能实现吗？
We have to.
‎必须要实现
Um, it seems like you're very optimistic.
‎你似乎非常乐观
Is that how I sound?
‎听起来是这样吗？
Yeah, I mean...
‎是 我是说… ‎我无法相信你一直这样说
I can't believe you keep saying that, because I'm like, "Really?
‎因为我在想：“真的吗？”
I feel like we're headed toward dystopia.
我感觉 ‎我们正走向毁灭而不是乌托邦
I feel like we're on the fast track to dystopia,
‎我感觉我们正在飞速走向毁灭
and it's gonna take a miracle to get us out of it."
‎需要一个奇迹 ‎才能让我们走下这条路“
And that miracle is, of course, collective will.
‎这个奇迹当然是集体意识
I am optimistic that we're going to figure it out,
‎可我是乐观主义者 ‎我们一定会有办法解决
but I think it's gonna take a long time.
‎但我认为 可能会用很久的时间
Because not everybody recognizes that this is a problem.
‎因为不是所有的人都意识到了 ‎这是一个问题
I think one of the big failures in technology today
‎我认为当今技术最大的一个失败
is a real failure of leadership,
‎是领导力的真正失败
of, like, people coming out and having these open conversations
‎人们站出来 去公开讨论
about things that... not just what went well, but what isn't perfect
‎不仅是哪些地方进行得好 ‎还应该讨论哪里不完美
so that someone can come in and build something new.
‎才能让有人介入 构建一些新的东西
At the end of the day, you know,
‎最终 你知道
this machine isn't gonna turn around until there's massive public pressure.
‎在有足够的公众压力之前 ‎这台机器是绝对不会回头的
By having these conversations and... and voicing your opinion,
‎通过这些对话 发出你的声音
in some cases through these very technologies,
‎在一些情况下 通过某些特定的技术
we can start to change the tide. We can start to change the conversation.
‎我们可以开始改变趋势 ‎我们可以开始改变对话
It might sound strange, but it's my world. It's my community.
‎听起来可能有点奇怪 ‎但这是我的世界 是我生活的环境
I don't hate them. I don't wanna do any harm to Google or Facebook.
‎我不恨他们 ‎我不想伤害谷歌或者脸书
I just want to reform them so they don't destroy the world. You know?
‎我只是想改革它们 ‎别让他们毁了世界 你知道吗？
I've uninstalled a ton of apps from my phone
‎我在手机上卸载了很多程序
that I felt were just wasting my time.
‎我感觉那些都是浪费时间
All the social media apps, all the news apps,
‎所有的社交媒体程序 所有的新程序
and I've turned off notifications
‎我关掉了通知
on anything that was vibrating my leg with information
‎所有那些让我手机震动的通知
that wasn't timely and important to me right now.
‎不够及时 对现在我来说 ‎并不重要的信息
It's for the same reason I don't keep cookies in my pocket.
‎也正是因为同样的理由 ‎我兜里不放饼干
Reduce the number of notifications you get.
‎减少你收到的通知数量
Turn off notifications.
‎关掉通知
Turning off all notifications.
‎关掉所有应用的通知
I'm not using Google anymore, I'm using Qwant,
‎我已经不再用谷歌了 ‎我用Qwant搜索引擎
which doesn't store your search history.
‎这个引擎不会存储你的搜索历史
Never accept a video recommended to you on YouTube.
‎永远不要接受 ‎YouTube上给你推荐的视频
Always choose. That's another way to fight.
‎永远自己去选择 ‎这是另一个抗争的方式
There are tons of Chrome extensions that remove recommendations.
‎谷歌浏览器有无数扩展程序 ‎可以移走推荐
You're recommending something to undo what you made.
‎我很喜欢你推荐一个 ‎撤销你所做东西的东西
Yep.
‎对
Before you share, fact  check, consider the source, do that extra Google.
‎在你分享之前 查找一下事实 ‎思考一下信息来源 谷歌搜索一下
If it seems like it's something designed to really push your emotional buttons,
‎如果这个东西感觉像是 ‎以触发你的情感按钮为目标
like, it probably is.
‎很可能确实是
Essentially, you vote with your clicks.
‎基本可以说 你用点击去投票
If you click on clickbait,
‎如果你点击了钓鱼链接
you're creating a financial incentive that perpetuates this existing system.
‎你就是在创造一个经济奖励 ‎延续这个已经存在的体系
Make sure that you get lots of different kinds of information
‎在你的生活中 一定要获得
in your own life.
‎各种不同的信息
I follow people on Twitter that I disagree with
‎我会在推特上关注我不认同的人
because I want to be exposed to different points of view.
‎因为我想看到不同的观点
Notice that many people in the tech industry
‎要知道 技术行业中的很多人
don't give these devices to their own children.
‎不会把这些设备给他们自己的小孩用
My kids don't use social media at all.
‎我的孩子们完全不使用社交媒体
Is that a rule, or is that a...
‎这是规定 还是…
That's a rule.
‎家规
We are zealots about it.
‎我们对它很狂热
We're... We're crazy.
‎我们很疯狂
And we don't let our kids have really any screen time.
‎我们不会让我们的孩子 ‎拥有任何看屏幕的时间
I've worked out what I think are three simple rules, um,
‎我想出了 ‎我自己认为的三个简单原则
that make life a lot easier for families and that are justified by the research.
‎能让生活对家人来说更容易 ‎这是经过研究验证的
So, the first rule is all devices out of the bedroom
‎第一个原则是 ‎在每晚的固定时间 所有设备
at a fixed time every night.
‎不能进入卧室
Whatever the time is, half an hour before bedtime, all devices out.
‎不管是什么时间 睡前半小时 ‎所有设备全都拿出去
The second rule is no social media until high school.
‎第二个原则是 ‎高中之前禁止使用社交媒体
Personally, I think the age should be 16.
‎我个人认为 这个年龄应该是16岁
Middle school's hard enough. Keep it out until high school.
‎初中已经够难了 上高中之前别用了
And the third rule is work out a time budget with your kid.
‎第三个原则是 ‎和你的孩子研究出一个时间预算
And if you talk with them and say,
‎如果你和他们聊 去说
"Well, how many hours a day do you wanna spend on your device?
‎“你每天想在你的设备上花多少时间
What do you think is a good amount? "
‎你觉得适合的时长是多少”
they'll often say something pretty reasonable.
‎他们通常会说出一个很合理的时长
Well, look, I know perfectly well
‎看 我非常清楚
that I'm not gonna get everybody to delete their social media accounts,
‎我无法让所有人删除社交媒体账号
but I think I can get a few.
‎但我想我可以让几个人这样做
And just getting a few people to delete their accounts matters a lot,
‎让几个人删除账号 ‎就已经能产生很大影响了
and the reason why is that that creates the space for a conversation
‎理由是 这样能创造一个对话的空间
because I want there to be enough people out in the society
‎因为我想让社会中有足够的人
who are free of the manipulation engines to have a societal conversation
‎这些人不受到引擎的操纵 ‎能够进行社交对话
that isn't bounded by the manipulation engines.
‎没有受到操纵引擎的牵制
So, do it! Get out of the system.
‎这样做吧！退出这个体系
Yeah, delete. Get off the stupid stuff.
‎对 删掉 下线这个愚蠢的东西
The world's beautiful. Look. Look, it's great out there.
‎世界很美丽 你们看 ‎外面的世界很美好